<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://barakuba.com/">
  <id>https://barakuba.com/</id>
  <title>Bára &amp; Kuba on the road :: The travel diary of two</title>
  <updated>2018-12-16T08:46:15Z</updated>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://barakuba.com/feed/index.xml"/>
  <author>
    <name>Barbora Hájková &amp; Jakub Chodounský</name>
    <uri>https://barakuba.com</uri>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2018-12-16:/trips/2018/12/16/west-coast-surf-trip/</id>
    <title type="html">West Coast Surf Trip</title>
    <published>2018-12-16T08:46:15Z</published>
    <updated>2018-12-16T08:46:15Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/12/16/west-coast-surf-trip/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/9.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/9.jpg" alt="West Coast Surf Trip" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a story of a few brave souls chasing waves on West Coast of South Island during one long weekend. How many smashed avocados on toast were consumed? Could they surf next to a blowhole? And did they manage to find the perfect&amp;nbsp;ride?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="overture"&gt;Overture&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Mate, you should come down for a surf,” a voice resonated through the telephone line with a great&amp;nbsp;enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah mate, I should come down for a surf,” I replied, hung up, and booked the cheapest flight to Christchurch where my friend Honza lives. What an awkward time to fly, but you can’t really complain for the&amp;nbsp;price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/14.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A stunning sunset through a small waterfall near Punakaiki" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/14.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A stunning sunset through a small waterfall near Punakaiki&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taking the fins off Rasta, my trusted fun board with plenty of volume to catch any tiny ripples, was a standard pre-flight routine. The water was still cold so I stuffed my board bag with all the necessary rubber – thick winter wetsuit, hoodie, and booties. Locals would give me a cheeky smirk while putting on a old beaten summer neoprene lined with holes as they consider 13°C water to be almost&amp;nbsp;summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The plan was solid. I fly down, and we decide what the plan is. Based on the swell. Catch the best&amp;nbsp;rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="west-coast"&gt;West&amp;nbsp;Coast&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Banks Peninsula was flat. Kaikoura could’ve been mistaken for a lake. And Dunedin wasn’t showing its finest. On the other hand, West Coast seemed promising. You never know until you arrive at the beach and see the waves with your own&amp;nbsp;eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/7.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A dark lush rainforest of close to the ocean" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/7.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A dark lush rainforest of close to the ocean&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;West Coast is a spooky place. It is remote with rough and rugged coastline. The swell is almost always too big and you need to wait for it to drop and there is lots of water moving. Most of the times you are surfing in this unusual cleansing solitude next to a pristine dark lush rainforest. It is pretty spiritual&amp;nbsp;experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/12.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rugged cliffs of limestone meet with the evening foam" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/12.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Rugged cliffs of limestone meet with the evening foam&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also there is a lot of marine life, from dolphins to giant seals and animals with big sharp teeth that feed on those giant seals. The shifting river banks featuring murky waters are adding to the mix of mysterious and chilling (literally as the rivers are flowing from one of many glaciers)&amp;nbsp;feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-crew"&gt;The&amp;nbsp;Crew&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stopped at a petrol station. Gauging each other with a bit of surfer’s smalltalk about the board volumes, shapes, and recent sessions. Tristan suddenly went silent. Squinting his eyes and letting the wind land on his cheek he started his divine&amp;nbsp;prophecy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/4.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Jay and Tristan, the watermen of South" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jay and Tristan, the watermen of South&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It looks like an offshore for the morning,” he whispered. All of us nodded in complete silence giving him utter respect for his arcane knowledge of the&amp;nbsp;weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For good waves you need a big storm far away from the shore to start pushing the waves towards the coast. When they are coming closer to the beach you need a little bit of local wind coming from the mainland to smooth them over. This is what Tristan was referring to as an offshore. That’s the secret ingredient to a perfect&amp;nbsp;ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Or not. You know, can be anything, really.” And we knew he was right. It could be&amp;nbsp;anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jay looked at him. “Yeah, bro. I guess we’ll just have to wait and see in the morning, aye?” and he puffed from his electronic cigarette. He was the most chilled person on the trip. You could always tell he’s around by the sweet smell of cherries from his vape. The only time I’ve seen him remotely close to being stressed was when he thought he lost his smoking device. It turned out to be in the pocket of his jacket. Phew, that was a close&amp;nbsp;one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Honza was the last one of the crew. He put the group together, organised the trip, and sorted out our sweet bunk accommodation. He’s probably one of the top Czech surfers. I mean he would make the top 100 for sure. I guess there would be like 100 Czechs surfing at least, right? Also, he has a great talent for losing his car keys which posed a challenge on the last day when we were chasing that brief window of morning offshore&amp;nbsp;winds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/13.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Loads of whitewater on a sandy beach with limestone rocks" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/13.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Loads of whitewater on a sandy beach with limestone rocks&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the winding road through Arthur’s Pass and a long drive we arrived to Punakaiki. It was late at night so we all went straight to&amp;nbsp;bed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="punakaiki-river"&gt;Punakaiki&amp;nbsp;River&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the early morning we went to check out the nearby spots. The first one we arrived at was this uninviting beach break next to Punakaiki River and the famous&amp;nbsp;blowholes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was gloomy, foggy, and there was a bit of drizzle. The true surfing weather for West Coast. We watched the waves for a bit. There was a lot of water moving and the sets were big but they didn’t happen too often. It was just us and the beach. Being the new guy on West Coast I asked Tristan and Jay what do they&amp;nbsp;think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/1.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Foggy hills around Punakaiki river" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Foggy hills around Punakaiki river&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You know, I reckon we either go in, or not. Either way,” said Tristan.&lt;br /&gt;
“Yeah bro, I’m totally easy,” replied Jay with&amp;nbsp;confidence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much wisdom and surfing knowledge in just those two sentences. I knew that I’m in the right company with these two experienced watermen of the South. In the end, we decided to go&amp;nbsp;in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/2.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Lots of water moving at this surf break" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Lots of water moving at this surf break&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paddling out was a mission. It was fine if you timed it well. You could avoid getting a wave on your head altogether. But if you were unlucky and the sets started rolling in it was almost impossible to get&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tristan and Honza were the first to paddle out. It looked easy as no sets came through. But they couldn’t catch a wave for at least 30 minutes. Me and Jay watched them and were considering our&amp;nbsp;options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/6.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hard work paddling out at Punakaiki river" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/6.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hard work paddling out at Punakaiki river&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then suddenly these giant walls started coming in. Take off as steep as you can imagine followed by a fast journey through a hollow pit. This nasty, grunty, and gnarly wave wasn’t there to mess around. If you were at a good spot you could squeeze into a small tube. Tristan caught the wave of the day – this head-high beast was steep and&amp;nbsp;fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Me and Jay set ourselves on the quest to paddle out in between the sets. It took us good three attempts to get out but eventually we made it to the back. With the roaring sound of waves breaking just a few meters away from us it was a good introduction to the West Coast&amp;nbsp;ruggedness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had a window of clean waves with light breezes of offshore. After a few rides the waves started closing out and there was no wave face to ride anymore. Everyone caught at least one decent ride so we happily got out of the water. It was one of these &lt;em&gt;happy that I made it back&lt;/em&gt;&amp;nbsp;feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/3.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="'Woot, woot!' the palms were cheering while Tristan was taming the beast" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&amp;#8216;Woot, woot!&amp;#8217; the palms were cheering while Tristan was taming the beast&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Let’s get a feed,” said Jay. And we went back to cook some eggs on avocado toast for late&amp;nbsp;breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="punakaiki-blowhole"&gt;Punakaiki&amp;nbsp;Blowhole&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we went to the other side of the pancake rocks and blowholes. The Punakaiki beach is a sandy break with a beautiful rocky point break on the left. During high tide you get back wash from the rocks and getting out of the water could be a bit of a&amp;nbsp;challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point was breaking far away from the shore but it offered long rides and clean faces. We didn’t hesitate and went for it straight away. The surf was still pumping with head-high waves, and maybe with a few overhead&amp;nbsp;sets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/10.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A beautiful left hand point break with long punchy rides" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/10.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A beautiful left hand point break with long punchy rides&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The easiest entry to the water was through sketchy boulders. You’d have to time it well and then jump and paddle for life. Otherwise you’d end up tumbling between big boulders and sharp reef rocks. Not a situation you’d wish to&amp;nbsp;experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tristan was the first one in the water and I followed shortly. Adrenaline was amped to the max while getting closer to the rocks. Time it well, jump, and paddle. Paddle fast into the safety of the deep&amp;nbsp;waters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/5.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The beginning of Pancake Rocks" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/5.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The beginning of Pancake Rocks&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The wave was a bit fat, but beautiful and punchy. It was glassy as and it had a kick. The rides were long with plenty of face to work with. Everyone was catching the waves and riding like there would be no tomorrow. With the arms out of jelly we all got out of the water a few hours later.&amp;nbsp;Smiling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the highlight of the trip. The reason why we came here. This is why we&amp;nbsp;surf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/19.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A bit of backwash coming from the rocks on high tide" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/19.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A bit of backwash coming from the rocks on high tide&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jay took a few puffs from his ever present ciggie. “Mate, I’m looking for a feed,&amp;nbsp;aye?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="westport"&gt;Westport&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the last evening, Tristan started “Like if I was here just by myself, and I know I’m not, I think I’d try to go early. You know. I mean if it was up to me, but it’s not. I’m easy, you&amp;nbsp;know.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at him with admiration and curiosity. “So, tomorrow, you wanna go early,&amp;nbsp;huh?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Ummm. Yeah, bro. But I’m&amp;nbsp;easy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/18.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A clean ground swell waves lining within a perfect period" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/18.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A clean ground swell waves lining within a perfect period&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone woke up with the chickens apart from Honza. But it didn’t took long and he came down just after Jay finished his morning brew followed by obligatory sweet cherry&amp;nbsp;smoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a while, he sadly admitted, “Guys, I can’t find the keys from the car.” And the classic search and rescue operation&amp;nbsp;began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After we found the keys, hidden flawlessly under the chair in the kitchen, we arrived to the point next to the blowholes. We surfed one more time having another great session and then we set off back to Christchurch. This time through Lewis Pass so we could check a few other spots on the&amp;nbsp;way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It started blowing onshore and the wind was killing the&amp;nbsp;waves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fox River, a long breaking river mouth with icy cold glacier water and hollow waves, wasn’t working. Nine mile beach didn’t look like much either. Tauranga Bay was surfable but after the perfect rides from the last two days Tristan&amp;nbsp;disapproved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Yeah mate, it doesn’t really spark my interest. If you know what I mean,” he judged the&amp;nbsp;swell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/15.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Limestone cliffs throughout the coast" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/15.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Limestone cliffs throughout the coast&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew what he meant and we ended up in Westport looking at Shingles and Breakwater. Breakwater was small but clean. The last chance for catching a few. Jay and Tristan chose to pass and we parted our ways. Honza and myself were in for one last session. The water was chilly as Buller River was flowing into the ocean next to us. There were a few decent peaks with few hollow&amp;nbsp;rides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a short session we decided it’s time to go back to&amp;nbsp;Christchurch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id="conclusion"&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days later the phone rang again. It was my mate&amp;nbsp;Honza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bro, was a good weekend, aye?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Nah, yeah bro. Was epic! Totes&amp;nbsp;rad.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/west-coast-surf-trip/16.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Where the ocean meets the land" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/west-coast-surf-trip/16.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Where the ocean meets the land&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hung up and looked into the distance. West Coast is harsh and primal in its essence. It is the most prestigious university of surfing. The Harvard and Oxford of New Zealand. When we left Christchurch we were just boys but we came back as&amp;nbsp;men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or most likely not. Whatevs. Nevertheless, we had heaps of&amp;nbsp;fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2018-11-09:/trips/2018/11/09/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/</id>
    <title type="html">Avalanche Peak and autumn in Arthur's Pass</title>
    <published>2018-11-09T05:13:10Z</published>
    <updated>2018-11-09T05:13:10Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/11/09/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/48.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/48.jpg" alt="Avalanche Peak and autumn in Arthur's Pass" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s a while ago when one of our friends moved from Wellington down to Christchurch and left his car with us. He asked us if we could drive it down during one of our trip and so we&amp;nbsp;did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/2.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="On the way to Arthur's Pass" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;On the way to Arthur&amp;#8217;s Pass&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We booked the &lt;a href="https://www.greatjourneysofnz.co.nz/interislander/"&gt;ferry&lt;/a&gt; and planned to make a stop in Arthur’s Pass on the way to Christchurch. So far, we only had done some small walks in the &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2015/10/15/road-trip-to-arthurs-path/"&gt;area&lt;/a&gt; and were keen to do some of longer&amp;nbsp;hikes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/16.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Steep hills of Southern Alps" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/16.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Steep hills of Southern Alps&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ferry anchored in Picton and we carried out via Nelson Lakes to Murchison and than down south to Jackson where we book accommodation at &lt;a href="https://jacksonsretreat.co.nz/"&gt;Jackson’s Retreat Alpine holiday park&lt;/a&gt;. This place is beside a wonderful forest with options for short walks and a few glow worm spots. The park’s communal areas are well equipped and everything was super clean. Furthermore the owners had a goat strolling around park and let everybody to rub&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/12.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The weather was perfect" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/12.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The weather was perfect&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day morning we moved on to Arthur’s Pass and went to a local &lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOC&lt;/span&gt; office to get more information about &lt;a href="https://www.doc.govt.nz/globalassets/documents/parks-and-recreation/tracks-and-walks/canterbury/waimakariri/arthurs-pass-brochure.pdf"&gt;hiking options&lt;/a&gt; and also to ask about the latest weather&amp;nbsp;forecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/15.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view towards Mt Rollston" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/15.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A view towards Mt Rollston&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the forecast said the morning clouds should clear out later in the day, we decided to climb up to &lt;a href="https://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/canterbury/places/arthurs-pass-national-park/things-to-do/tracks/avalanche-peak-route/"&gt;Avalanche Peak&lt;/a&gt; and return via Scotts Track. The entire walk was estimated to take between 6 and 8 hours, so we packed our backpacks and set&amp;nbsp;off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/25.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view of Lyell Peak" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/25.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A view of Lyell Peak&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no easy warm up, the track immediately started to climb up. More than once we had to use our hands to swing up large steps. As we ascended through the forest, we could see waterfalls along Avalanche Creek every now and then. We made a few short breaks but after an hour or so, we finally made it to the&amp;nbsp;bushline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/13.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Terrain was not easy -- steep and rough" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/13.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Terrain was not easy &amp;#8211; steep and rough&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even from here views were amazing but we still had about 700m of elevation ahead of us. From this point the track followed the ridge line and every moment we stopped and turned back to have a look&amp;nbsp;around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple of hundred meters below the summit the ridge flattened so our legs could have a rest before the final part. It wasn’t my favourite section because we had to climb up through bluffs with sheer slopes either&amp;nbsp;side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/30.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Devils Punchbowl Falls" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/30.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Devils Punchbowl Falls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, our effort was rewarded with an amazing 360° view. The sky was clear without a single cloud and some of shaded hills were still covered by snow patches. With such views our summit lunch tasted much&amp;nbsp;better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/26.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A photo on the summit was necessary" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/26.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A photo on the summit was necessary&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After resting and taking enough pictures we headed back to Arthur’s Pass via Scott’s track. As the track path runs along the neighbouring ridge, we could enjoy the views before we got below bush line. The track was also considerably less steep then the one we had climbed on the way&amp;nbsp;up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/40.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Waimakariri River Valley" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/40.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Waimakariri River Valley&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A couple times we could see Devils Punchbowl Falls through clearings in the bush on the other side of the valley. After an hour we met the main road and it took about extra 10 minutes to get back to our car parked near visitor&amp;nbsp;centre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/49.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="On the way to Christchurch" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/avalanche-peak-and-autumn-in-arthurs-pass/49.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;On the way to Christchurch&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would not be a proper hike without a treat at the end so we grabbed a scoop of ice-cream at a local cafe. After that we could head off to Christchurch and hand the car&amp;nbsp;over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2018-10-14:/trips/2018/10/14/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/</id>
    <title type="html">New Caledonia&amp;#58; vanilla from Lifou and vibrant Noumea</title>
    <published>2018-10-14T05:11:22Z</published>
    <updated>2018-10-14T05:11:22Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/10/14/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/133.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/133.jpg" alt="New Caledonia&amp;#58; vanilla from Lifou and vibrant Noumea" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we’d been planning our trip to Caledonia we’d decided that it would be worth including a visit of one of those tiny little islands near Grande Terre. After looking at our options and trying to find the best fit for our schedule we picked Lifou, one of Loyalty&amp;nbsp;Islands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/31.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of Lifou from the plane on the way to Noumea" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/31.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;View of Lifou from the plane on the way to Noumea&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/06/12/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/"&gt;Great South&lt;/a&gt; we headed early in the morning straight to the Magenta airport in Noumea. The flight with Air Caledonia to Lifou was definitely not the cheapest transport option we could have chosen ($450 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NZD&lt;/span&gt; return for 2 people) but given that we didn’t have too much time it was better than spending hours on a ferry. Moreover, I liked the idea that we were going to have a view of islands from the bird&amp;nbsp;perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/33.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Coast of Lifou" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/33.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Coast of Lifou&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The flight was smooth and we had a really good view of the mountain range on Grand Terre as well as island’s coastlines. Shades of blue between deep and shallow spots in the ocean were&amp;nbsp;amazing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/131.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Blue sky and crystal clear water of Lifou" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/131.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Blue sky and crystal clear water of Lifou&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To travel easily around Lifou we’d booked a &lt;a href="https://www.iles-loyaute.com/fr/lifou/transport?view=prestataire&amp;amp;idprestataire=2868"&gt;car&lt;/a&gt;. After arrival, we managed to find our rental but a guy who ran the place obviously didn’t know much about our booking. Still, during a few minutes, he got a car with a full tank from somewhere. When we asked him about lit warning signs on the car’s dashboard which were indicating that something is not quite right he just said: “No problem”. Well, in the end, he was right, we wouldn’t have any car related issues on the way, but at that moment it made us a bit&amp;nbsp;nervous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/128.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Colonial architecture" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/128.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Colonial architecture&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the airport, we drove to a &lt;a href="https://www.newcaledonia.travel/en/business-directory/activities/maison-de-la-vanille-des-iles-loyaute"&gt;vanilla house&lt;/a&gt; near Hnathalo. The minute we arrived we knew it’s a trap. A tourist trap. As a large group of tourists from a nearby cruise ship queued for snack. Jakub queued as well and got a free biscuit. We had a quick look at the gift shop and decided that it’s not for us and we rather move on without a tour around a&amp;nbsp;plantation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/124.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="An old well no longer in use" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/124.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;An old well no longer in use&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We headed down to the south until we reached the coast. As well as on the mainland it surprised us how many wreckages we passed. Most of them were old&amp;nbsp;busses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/127.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bus wrecks were all around the island" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/127.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bus wrecks were all around the island&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the coast, we stopped at a couple of beautiful white sand beaches. We chose one of them and went snorkeling. The water was crystal clear but pretty chilly. We definitely expected it to be a bit warmer. But fish and coral were&amp;nbsp;beautiful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/129.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ready for snorkeling" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/129.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ready for snorkeling&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We spend a night at &lt;a href="https://www.newcaledonia.travel/en/business-directory/accomodations/chez-waka"&gt;Chez Waka&lt;/a&gt;. The place was lovely. It had all we needed – a clean bathroom, an equipped kitchen, a beach just a couple of meters away. We stayed in our tent but the place also offered an accommodation in tribal style houses. The only con was that Jakub wanted to try a local specialty – le crabe cocotier – which I’d asked for when booking but a lady who owned the place had probably forgotten. Une catastrophe&amp;nbsp;grande!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/138.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sunset on the beach at Chez Waka" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/138.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunset on the beach at Chez Waka&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, the next day she organized a private tour to a small vanilla house just a few minutes away. In the morning, a woman welcomed us to her house and guided us through her plantation. A conversation was a bit tough as she only spoke French but with a help of Google translator we managed to ask questions and learned some interesting facts about vanilla. In the end, we didn’t avoid being offered some souvenirs to buy but it was much nicer than the vanilla house we had seen the previous&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/148.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="On vanilla plantation" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/148.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;On vanilla plantation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we finished the tour we still had a couple of hours before taking a flight back to the main island. So, we visited a few interesting spots around the island, had lunch on the beach and a short dip in the cool water before we headed to the&amp;nbsp;airport.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/145.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bara attempting pollination" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/145.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bara attempting pollination&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Noumea, we booked an accommodation through &lt;a href="https://www.airbnb.co.nz/rooms/20626235?location=Noumea%2C%20South%20Province%2C%20New%20Caledonia&amp;amp;s=LInZo6A7"&gt;Airbnb&lt;/a&gt;. The place was very basic but it had all we needed and not too far from city center. After checking in, we drove through the city to Baie des Citrons. It is an easily accessible, sheltered beach and as it was weekend there was a plenty of people enjoying nice weather, jumping in the water or just sitting on the sand and eating an&amp;nbsp;ice-cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We grabbed our snorkeling gear and jumped into the water. Corrals were a bit further from the coast but we saw different species of fish and Jakub spotted a turtle. He didn’t talk about anything else for rest of the day. In fact, he still talks about the turtle from time to&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/156.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Traditional Kanak houses" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/156.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Traditional Kanak houses&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later in the afternoon, we decided to visit the &lt;a href="https://www.newcaledonia.travel/nz/noumea/tjibaou-cultural-center"&gt;Tjibaou Cultural Centre&lt;/a&gt;. The centre itself is located aside from the city and it is a combination of a museum, performance space and park. The Mwakaa area was an interesting insight into Kanak architecture. It displays different types of Kanak tradition houses as their design differs depending on the&amp;nbsp;region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/153.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Tjibaou Cultural Centre" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/153.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Tjibaou Cultural Centre&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back to the car, we walked via Kanak Pathway which winded through the park. It was designed to create an educational journey of native flora and its importance in Kanak culture. Definitely a nice stroll. I liked the design of the main cultural center building which supposed to blend Kanak tradition and contemporary art but unfortunately, we found most of the exhibitions inside quite boring. So, not really sure if the visit was worth the&amp;nbsp;money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/159.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Last dinner in Noumea" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/159.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Last dinner in Noumea&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up our trip with an amazing dinner in one of the restaurants located along the promenade at Baie des Citrons before heading back to our&amp;nbsp;accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/157.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="See you next time New Caledonia" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-vanilla-from-lifou-and-vibrant-noumea/157.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;See you next time New Caledonia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day we had time only for a quick coffee at L’Annexe at Coconut Palm Square but then we had to go straight to the airport to catch a plane back to New&amp;nbsp;Zealand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2018-06-11:/trips/2018/06/12/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/</id>
    <title type="html">New Caledonia&amp;#58; magnificent colours of Great South</title>
    <published>2018-06-11T22:34:30Z</published>
    <updated>2018-06-11T22:34:30Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/06/12/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/112.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/112.jpg" alt="New Caledonia&amp;#58; magnificent colours of Great South" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We woke up early. The raindrops were quietly hitting the top layer of our tent and the air was fresh. By the time we sat down in kitchen shelter and ate our breakfast, it was pouring down with the&amp;nbsp;rain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/106.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Once we got further inland the weather looked promising" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/106.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Once we got further inland the weather looked promising&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We packed the wet tent and left Dumbea. We had about 24 hours to see as much of south Grand Terre as possible and the schedule was stretched. It became even tighter after we spent about an hour and a half stuck in a traffic jam around&amp;nbsp;Noumea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, we get out of the urban area, passed Mont-Dore covered by cloud and were moving on through hilly landscape. Soon, the green colour of surrounding vegetation stepped back and patches of red soil became dominant. Compared to lush &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/04/30/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/"&gt;east coast&lt;/a&gt; this part of the island looked&amp;nbsp;scorched.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/105.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A red soil reminded us of Australia" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/105.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A red soil reminded us of Australia&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just before we reached Lac de Yaté we turned left on the road to Parc de la Rivière Bleue. It is the biggest park in New Caledonia and the main attraction in Great South. To avoid crowds it is best to start your visit early in the morning. We didn’t manage to do that but because of shoulder season, we hardly met any other&amp;nbsp;people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/118.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Red, green and blue colours of Great South region" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/118.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Red, green and blue colours of Great South region&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the main entrance, we bought tickets and quickly headed off to Pont Perignon which was where the bus tour around the park departed from. At first, we were worried that we had been waiting at the wrong spot but after a few minutes, a bus arrived. As it was only us on the bus we had a private&amp;nbsp;tour.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bus driver tried to tell us some interesting facts about the park and its wildlife but communication was a bit complicated as our French was a bit poor and his English was even worse. But with the aid of gesticulation and body language, we learnt some&amp;nbsp;stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/89.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Drowned forest during the dry season" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/89.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Drowned forest during the dry season&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made a couple of short stops around the park. The first location was the drowned forest which is a field of dry, bleached thin tree trunks sticking out of the ground. After the construction of Yate Dam, the water level rose up and trees got flooded. However, as we visited the park during a dry season, there were only puddles of water among&amp;nbsp;trees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We made another stop at a giant kauri tree and a bit further our guide took us for a short walk through bush and tried to look for a &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kagu"&gt;cagou&lt;/a&gt;, a symbol of New Caledonia. Although he really made an effort – he was whistling, calling and hitting the ground with a stick – we didn’t see a&amp;nbsp;bird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/90.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A big kauri tree" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/90.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A big kauri tree&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we reached the end of gravel road we had about an hour to explore the surrounding before the bus would come back to pick us up. We found a lovely spot near the river. It was not hot enough to jump into the crystal clear water but along with birds singing in the bush, it created an amazing atmosphere to just sit and&amp;nbsp;chill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The trails in the park are ideal for cycling which would give us more flexibility but unfortunately, we didn’t have so much time to spend there a whole&amp;nbsp;day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/91.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Crystal water of Bleue RIver" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/91.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Crystal water of Bleue RIver&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we returned back to our car, we did a bit more self-guided exploring and drove around the park. We stopped at a couple of viewpoints. The contrast of red, green and blue colours of surrounding landscape was amazing and the place really reminds us of Australia. Most of the time we were alone and hardly met any other&amp;nbsp;visitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/114.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Looking out for bright future" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/114.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Looking out for bright future&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the park, we carried on along the lakeside and a winding road led us to a massive concrete wall – the Yate dam. On east, we could see the ocean on the horizon. The water from the lake ran via a nice green valley which we had a better view of as we descended down to the town of&amp;nbsp;Yate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/120.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Yate dam" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/120.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Yate dam&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was not much in Yate itself. It is a sleepy town. When we asked a lady at a local grocery store for directions, she struggled to find the town. After that, we rather head to our&amp;nbsp;campsite.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/122.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="We had some amazing views of Lake Yate" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/122.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We had some amazing views of Lake Yate&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Les Bois Du Sud campsite was a beautiful place surrounded by bush. We’d arrived just on time to catch up with a ranger before his shift finished and he headed off. We were the only overnight guests there which was a bit&amp;nbsp;scary&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/96.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Happy campers" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-magnificent-colours-of-great-south/96.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Happy campers&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, everything went well and the next day in the morning we woke up super early to hit the road back to Noumea. We had a plane to catch. Next destination –&amp;nbsp;Lifou.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2018-04-29:/trips/2018/04/30/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/</id>
    <title type="html">New Caledonia&amp;#58; lush rain forest and desolated mines of East Coast</title>
    <published>2018-04-29T20:18:16Z</published>
    <updated>2018-04-29T20:18:16Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/04/30/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/21.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/21.jpg" alt="New Caledonia&amp;#58; lush rain forest and desolated mines of East Coast" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In morning, we left &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/02/13/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/"&gt;Koumac&lt;/a&gt; and drove across the top of the island towards. A surrounding land was covered with half-dead trees sticking out of charcoal coloured soil. The vegetation was very sparse in this part of country. We passed a worryingly high number of car wrecks along the road. Some were remains of car accident but others were probably just dumped there to get rid of an useless&amp;nbsp;vehicle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/74.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A sad fate -- cars like this were not an exception" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/74.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A sad fate &amp;#8211; cars like this were not an exception&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past, this part of island was a significant mining region but it also left its marks on landscape and we were wondering how many tourist get around. Those views were not from a travel&amp;nbsp;brochure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/46.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Black soil and burned vegetation -- you don’t find these pictures in tour brochures" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/46.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Black soil and burned vegetation &amp;#8211; you don’t find these pictures in tour brochures&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, once we got to Ouegoa – a historical copper and gold rush town – and near the coast, the amount of rainfall got higher and everything was greener. We stopped at a couple of desolate beaches. The views of palm trees bending down water and rapidly rising hillsides were spectacular. We had a quick dip in the ocean but then moved on to the next stop – Tao&amp;nbsp;waterfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/18.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The next stop -- Tao waterfall" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/18.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The next stop &amp;#8211; Tao waterfall&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were many waterfalls along the road but this one was easily accessible from and was definitely worth stopping by. We spent there a good half an hour hopping from boulder to boulder and dipping in clean&amp;nbsp;water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/52.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A great place for a refreshing dip" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/52.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A great place for a refreshing dip&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got back to the car we carried on to Ouaième ferry. It is the last working Caledonian ferry and should be soon replaced by a bridge. The ferry was small and fitted only a couple of vehicles but operates 24/7 and it was&amp;nbsp;free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/20.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ouaième ferry -- according to local tribes also the place is where the entrance to the land of dead people is found" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/20.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ouaième ferry &amp;#8211; according to local tribes also the place is where the entrance to the land of dead people is found&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived in Hienghene, where we made our next stop. The town is located on the edge of Hienghene river mouth and is popular for its limestone rock formation called La Poule. The stone which sits in the lagoon is easily spotted from lookouts along the road or there was an option to hire a kayak and paddle around. But we skipped that and after a lunch we moved&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/61.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="La Poule -- the famous Hienghène's brooding hen" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/61.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;La Poule &amp;#8211; the famous Hienghène&amp;#8217;s brooding hen&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took us a couple more hours before we arrived in Port De Poindimié where we were going to stay over the night. &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/Camping-de-Tiakan-1665197317053742/"&gt;The Camp De Tiakan&lt;/a&gt; was an amazing spot situated in a palm grove right next to the beach. The only worry was not being hit by falling coconuts. We picked a site with a view of ocean and in the evening we watched the sunset while having dinner. It was definitely the best campsite during our stay in Caledonia. Basic but beautiful and&amp;nbsp;clean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/64.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A top spot for the romantic sunset -- Camp De Tiakan" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/64.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A top spot for the romantic sunset &amp;#8211; Camp De Tiakan&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, we had to set off early as there was a lot of driving and we had to get back on west coast. Before we left the coast and started to go up to the central  mountain range we had stopped at Ba waterfall near Meomo village. The waterfall was off the main road and an access path to it looked a bit dodgy. But luckily nobody kicked us&amp;nbsp;out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/70.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ba waterfall" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/70.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ba waterfall&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Poro the road started to climb up and we entered the mining region again. In this part of the country, the mining of nickel has been going on since 1980s’. The landscape there looked terrible, especially in the contrast with the fresh and green upper east coast we had just came from. Down here, there was no vegetation. The dry red soil was separated by deep gullies modelled by erosion. Now and then we could see large diggers operating in the&amp;nbsp;distance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/72.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Exhausted landscape near Poro village" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/72.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Exhausted landscape near Poro village&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point we got a bit nervous about the lack of petrol in our car. The car fuel consumption was quite high in the hills and no petrol station was anywhere near. And we definitely didn’t want to be stuck here. Luckily, we soon passed the summit and slowly descended to west&amp;nbsp;coast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/79.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="On the way back to the west coast" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/79.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;On the way back to the west coast&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we reached the coast, we had made a turn to a small town called Farino where we wanted to visit a giant fern park. Unfortunately, a hunting had been in progress and people were not let in due to safety reasons. Then we had to be happy with a near walk to a Farino waterfall. The easy trail followed the bank of the creak before reaching a small waterfall. A whole way a dog accompanied us as a local&amp;nbsp;guide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/84.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Farino waterfall" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-lush-rain-forest-and-desolated-mines-of-east-coast/84.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Farino waterfall&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got back to the carpark it was late afternoon and we still had a couple of hours of driving ahead of us. Once we reached the west coast we merge into highway and the rest of the way passed much quicker. Just before the dusk we arrived in &lt;a href="https://www.newcaledonia.travel/en/business-directory/accomodations/gaia-pacific"&gt;Dumbea&lt;/a&gt; where we stayed over the night. The Gaia Pacific campsite was basic but clean and quiet place. Apart from us, there were only two more&amp;nbsp;tents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned as the next destination will be – the Great&amp;nbsp;South!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2018-02-13:/trips/2018/02/13/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/</id>
    <title type="html">New Caledonia&amp;#58; scorched land and white beaches of West Coast</title>
    <published>2018-02-13T08:50:31Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-13T08:50:31Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/02/13/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/23.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/23.jpg" alt="New Caledonia&amp;#58; scorched land and white beaches of West Coast" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2015/11/22/bali-from-temple-to-waterfall-and-rice-fields/"&gt;Bali&lt;/a&gt; and Samoa we looked for our next holiday destination. The priorities were that a final destination would offer various things to do and also that we would not have to spend hours on a plane to get there. We investigated our options, did some research and eventually chose New&amp;nbsp;Caledonia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/8.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view during our lunch break" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/8.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A view during our lunch break&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our early joy from a purchase of cheap flight tickets immediately changed for the annoyance when we realized that each of us had two tickets to Noumea, the capital of New Caledonia, but none back to New Zealand. Usually helpful customer service from Air New Zealand was a bit hopeless this time but in the end, we got our return tickets and were all ready to&amp;nbsp;go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/6.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="We are on the road again" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/6.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;We are on the road again&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we planned to travel around the island, we booked a &lt;a href="https://www.airportrentals.com/"&gt;car&lt;/a&gt; in advance. In total, we were going to stay for 7 days, not much time then. Therefore, due to the fact that we were going to spend most of the time on the road, and also because of high prices of accommodation, we decided to camp. New Caledonia has quite a good network of campgrounds and holiday parks. Apart from that, we also read other people’s reviews and tried to avoid the ugly&amp;nbsp;places.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/10.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A bunch of locals at Base Nautique de Ouano " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/10.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A bunch of locals at Base Nautique de Ouano &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;October and November are probably the best months to visit the islands. The temperatures are nice and it is the least rainy period of the year. Although, it might be too dry, as we realised later. The day before our flight, there were extensive bushfires between the international airport and the capital. Luckily for us, we were going to head the opposite direction up north&amp;nbsp;first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/21.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Resilient vegetation" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/21.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Resilient vegetation&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the international airport in La Tontouta we picked up a car, bought some food in a nearby supermarket, and started our adventure. But no real adventure starts with empty belly and so shortly, we turned off the main road and drove to the beach to have lunch. The menu was a baguette, cheese, and paté. A combination which we repeated with little deviations every day for the whole&amp;nbsp;week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/12.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A beautiful view from Pointe Sauveur" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/12.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A beautiful view from Pointe Sauveur&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was Ouano’s mangroves. This extensive swampy area is a unique environment and home of wealthy fauna and flora. There are three short educative walks with a number of informative plaques. We chose one of the walks. On the way, we saw heaps of small crabs moving with amazing speed across the muddy surface before disappearing in one of small holes under the ground. Later, we drove along the beach to Pointe Sauveur – a lookout providing stunning views – and also stopped at Plage de Ouano to cool our&amp;nbsp;feet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/17.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ouano’s mangroves" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/17.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ouano’s mangroves&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We moved on via La Foa where we supplied food and passed a local monument – the Marguerite bridge. Although, we didn’t find it worth stopping. In Moindou, we made another turn off the road and headed inland to the royal palm forest. The royal palms are the local pride and we spotted them easily standing out from the rest of the&amp;nbsp;vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/18.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A royal palm grove" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/18.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A royal palm grove&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of more hours, just before Bourail, we turned left to Poé Beach. There was a campsite which we’d booked for the first night – &lt;a href="https://www.newcaledonia.travel/en/business-directory/accomodations/le-reve-de-nemo"&gt;La Reve de Nemo&lt;/a&gt;. It was a nice and tidy place only a few meters from the beach where we could watch a&amp;nbsp;sunset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/22.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A traditional Kanak house" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/22.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A traditional Kanak house&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting thing about the lifestyle of locals is that they get up early. Very early. Between 5-6am. Luckily, thanks to the time difference between Caledonia and New Zealand, we didn’t mind that because it felt like 7-8am to&amp;nbsp;us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/13.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Somewhere on the way" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/13.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Somewhere on the way&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started the second day with the Three Bays track. Getting up early had one advantage – the cooler weather. As the track went up and down between the bays it was definitely more pleasant to do it in the morning than under the midday sun. The track provided some beautiful views and we explored small beaches which we had just for ourselves because nobody else was there. The only downside was that we didn’t spot any turtles which sometimes come&amp;nbsp;there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/33.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Three Bays Track" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/33.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Three Bays Track&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before midday, we were back on the road and headed further north. As we were passing through the scorched landscape we were more and more surprised what a massive barrier the central mountain range is. All the rain is caught on its other site. When we drove through the section where the ground was burned and tree trunks were black with dry leaves, the entire picture looked really&amp;nbsp;depressive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/37.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The land after ravaging of bushfire -- we saw a few of them " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/37.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The land after ravaging of bushfire &amp;#8211; we saw a few of them &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we arrived at Voh, we made a break for a walk up to the near hill. A guide book said it would provide a view of famous Heart of Voh. Initially, I had thought that we would break our piggy bank and took a flight in an ultralight over the area. It would possibly provide the best views of the landmark as well as a view of deep sea blue holes but unfortunately the weather was not very impressive and we decided the flight was not worth the fortune. Instead, we tried to drive up to the lookout but our tiny Peugeot 108 was definitely not a right car for a crossing of half a meter deep gullies. So, we drove back, parked at the bottom and walked up&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/N10.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Can you find a heart?" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/N10.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Can you find a heart?&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, we got some good views but from the elevation, almost everything resembled a flat clearing of a heart shape and we could only guess which was the famous&amp;nbsp;one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there we carried on to Koumac where we’d booked a site in &lt;a href="https://www.petitfute.com/v52539-koumac-98850/c1166-hebergement/c1047-camping-hotellerie-de-plein-air/c178-camping/275101-gite-du-lagon.html"&gt;Gite Du Lagon&lt;/a&gt;. The campground was very basic. It was located next to the beach which was not particularly pretty but it had all we needed. An owner was a nice guy who we had a good chat&amp;nbsp;with.
We wrapped the day up with dinner in Koumac Marina where we enjoyed another portion of baguette while watching a wonderful sunset and listening to waves lapping against the&amp;nbsp;beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/40.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Baguette, pâté, and sunset" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/new-caledonia-scorched-land-and-beautiful-beaches-of-west-coast/40.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Baguette, pâté, and sunset&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day we were going to drive across the top of the island and explore the fresh green east coast. More about that&amp;nbsp;soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2018-02-03:/trips/2018/02/03/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; busy life of the Mekong delta</title>
    <published>2018-02-03T05:12:53Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-03T05:12:53Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/02/03/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/164.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/164.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; busy life of the Mekong delta" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After two weeks in northern Vietnam, we flew from &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt; down south to Ho Chi Minh to spend the rest of our trip there. To keep the expenses low, we chose the Jetstar airlines for our flight. They are cheap but not particularly reliable and so, it didn’t surprise us when we took off with two hours delay. Classic&amp;nbsp;Jetstar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/158.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A floating market with all different kind of goods" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/158.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A floating market with all different kind of goods&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the airport in Ho Chi Minh, we wanted to avoid a hassle with bargaining the price of a taxi and used the Uber instead. We didn’t have to negotiate the price but talking to the driver on phone and finding the car was not easy&amp;nbsp;either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we knew that we would arrive late at night, we’d booked our &lt;a href="https://www.agoda.com/vinh-chung-hotel/hotel/ho-chi-minh-city-vn.html?cid=-177"&gt;hotel&lt;/a&gt; in advance. Rooms were very simple, nothing luxurious, but they were clean, had windows and most importantly – an&amp;nbsp;air-conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/166.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="One of smaller boats got closer to try to sell some of their fruit" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/166.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One of smaller boats got closer to try to sell some of their fruit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next day we’d planned a trip to the Mekong Delta. A man picked us up early in the morning at our hotel and took us to a meeting point where we waited for a transport. For all our organized trips we always required to be a part of a very small group and so far it had always worked out. Until that time! A large packed bus with 30 other people&amp;nbsp;arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after being squeezed on the bus for a few hours, we arrived at Cai Be where the hot air slapped us immediately when we got off. We boarded a motorized boat and headed to the floating market. Each of oncoming boats was loaded with different types of fruit or vegetable and sellers kept trying to slip the samples of their goods to us from tall wooden poles. After a while, we parked next to one of the boats and had a chance to buy some of the tasty&amp;nbsp;stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/159.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A refreshing coconut water" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/159.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A refreshing coconut water&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried on to a rice noodles and a paper factory. But, before that we had to have a useless 30 minutes break inside a souvenir&amp;nbsp;shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The factory itself, which was rather a small backyard workshop than anything else, was quite interesting place. Both our guide and workers made an effort to explain and to show us a whole process of making the noodles and the rice paper. Volunteers could even try to make the paper on their own. Aside the other workers prepared coconut candies. We tasted a few  pieces along with some other pastries but all of them were too way too&amp;nbsp;sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/168.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A process of making rice noodles" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/168.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A process of making rice noodles&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, we hopped back on the boat and it took us to a different place where we had lunch. Again, all the food was delicious. The most interesting was a fish. At first, we hesitated to eat it because it looked a bit dodgy but then we plucked up the&amp;nbsp;courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/163.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Our lunch included a local fish" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/163.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our lunch included a local fish&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we had a choice to go for a short push bike ride. The bikes were not in the best condition but good enough for a small loop in near surrounding before we headed back to the&amp;nbsp;boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cruised for a few minutes before we got to our next stop. There, we were given traditional cone hats and got into small rowing boats operated by paddling women. They manoeuvred us through narrow river canals surrounded by dense vegetation before we got to a small wharf. From there we walked back to our boat on dry ground with a small stop for a cultural performance which was not very good&amp;nbsp;though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/162.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A part of the tour was also a demonstration from local beekeeper " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/162.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A part of the tour was also a demonstration from local beekeeper &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the last stop for the day. After returning back to the main wharf the bus supposed to take us to our accommodation. Or at least that’s what we thought was a plan. Instead, we stopped in the middle of nowhere and our guide told us we have to swap a bus because that  one was going to go back to Ho Chi Minh. We had to run across a busy four-lane highway, including climbing over concrete panels and waited in a odd place for a second bus. Luckily, it came soon and a couple of hours later we finally got to our hotel in Can&amp;nbsp;Tho.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/161.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Packaging of coconut candies " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/161.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Packaging of coconut candies &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dinner, which was an interesting seafood hot pot, we went for a walk on a nice waterfront along the city’s river. It was full of busy bars and&amp;nbsp;restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part of the tour we started the next day early in the morning. The bus full of other people picked us up and we headed to the wharf where a boat had been already waiting for&amp;nbsp;us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/167.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rice paper drying on the sun" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/167.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Rice paper drying on the sun&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cruised one of the river branches for about an hour before we made a break at a fruit orchard. It was a nice walk among fruit trees concluded with a fruit tasting and opportunity to buy some exotic pieces. No doubts that the prices were much higher than&amp;nbsp;usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got back to our boat we kept cruising for another hour but then it was time to slowly get back to our bus and head to Ho Chi&amp;nbsp;Minh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/155.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ho CHi Minh -- Post Office" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/155.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ho CHi Minh &amp;#8211; Post Office&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the trip was an interesting insight into life in delta but its value was degraded especially due to a very big group of people on the tour, too much waiting and useless stops at souvenir shops or because of that weird transport organization. Those things definitely need some&amp;nbsp;improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-11-27:/trips/2017/11/27/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; cruising in Bai Tu Long</title>
    <published>2017-11-27T08:17:39Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-27T08:17:39Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/11/27/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/142.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/142.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; cruising in Bai Tu Long" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we’d been organizing our trip to Ha Long Bay I was full of doubts. Many resources referred to the place as a location with thousands of tourist and hundreds of boats which cruise the bay all day long. After reading different resources and reviews we’d decided to do an overnight cruise in less known Bai Tu Long. It was a good&amp;nbsp;choice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/146.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="What a day for a cruise" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/146.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;What a day for a cruise&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our trip was organized via &lt;a href="http://www.vietnamista.cz/news/cely-clanek/"&gt;Mrs Mai&lt;/a&gt;. Early in the morning, a guide picked us up at our accommodation in &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt; and we headed to Ha Long city. It took a few hours, so we arrived at Hon Gai wharf about midday. Within 15 minutes we were already boarding on a small boat which was going to take us to our wooden cruise boat. No&amp;nbsp;delays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/141.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A busy spot near Thien Canh Son cave" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/141.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A busy spot near Thien Canh Son cave&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beside us, there was only one Australian couple and a crew. It was almost like having a private trip. No crowds, no people stepping on each other’s&amp;nbsp;heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cabins looked amazing. Wooden interior, a double bed, a nice bathroom and a big window for a proper view. We were chilling out only for a couple of minutes when somebody knocked on the door and announced the lunch&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/136.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside our cabin" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/136.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside our cabin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we went out on deck to admire the beautiful scenery. Rugged islands of different sizes and shapes were jutting all around and water sparkle in the afternoon sunshine. We could not have had the better&amp;nbsp;weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/145.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Chilling on the deck" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/145.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Chilling on the deck&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We anchored near Thien Canh Son cave. A small boat took us to the shore and with our guide, we climbed stairs up to the cave entrance. It was the only time that day when we had to interact with a bunch of other tourists. The cave itself was nice but nothing amazing. But it had an interesting history. Before listed in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt;, the cave served as a party venue. Due to that fact, some formations inside the cave suffered from&amp;nbsp;vandalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/143.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Thien Canh Son cave " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/143.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Thien Canh Son cave &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we returned back to the boat it was time to do some exercise! We got on kayaks and paddled around one of the small islands. I was quite surprised how clean the water was. We only saw a couple of floating plastic bottles and packages. It was a big difference compared to rest of the countryside overloaded which garbage. It didn’t take long and we were jumping from the boat deck into the deep&amp;nbsp;water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/144.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A bit of exercise before Happy Hour" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/144.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A bit of exercise before Happy Hour&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the sunset, we joined some of our crew members for squid fishing. While they were attracting the squids with a torch, we were trying to catch them with a simple bamboo stick and a hook made of a wire. It seemed hopeless but eventually, Jakub caught one! Next day it was served for&amp;nbsp;lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/137.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A chef prepared a yummy lunch" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/137.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A chef prepared a yummy lunch&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night on the boat was great. While anchored in a sheltered area, the boat hardly swayed and the next day we realized that we were moving only because of a roaring&amp;nbsp;engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, we headed to Vung Vieng floating village. We got on a small rowing boat and paddled through small settlement. The houses were tiny, usually one bedroom with hammocks on front deck. Some households even had a dog but we felt a bit sorry for them as their movement was restricted to floating&amp;nbsp;boardwalks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/152.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Vung Vieng floating village" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/152.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Vung Vieng floating village&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole place was really quiet and peaceful which was in high contrast with busy La Ha Long. The journey to the village ended with dipping through the cave carved through one of the rocky&amp;nbsp;pillars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/153.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rowing through the arc near floating Vung Vieng village" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/153.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Rowing through the arc near floating Vung Vieng village&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we returned back to our boat, it was time to check out from our rooms. From floating village, we were heading back to the wharf. We had one more delicious lunch (including Jakub’s squid) and after that, we just hung around on the deck and enjoyed the&amp;nbsp;view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/147.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A beautiful sunset in Bai Tu Long" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/147.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A beautiful sunset in Bai Tu Long&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our driver picked us up at the harbor and we drove back to Hanoi. In the evening we were going to catch a plane to Ho Chi Minh where we would stay until the end of the&amp;nbsp;trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-11-07:/trips/2017/11/07/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; a cup of tea in Moc Chau</title>
    <published>2017-11-07T08:47:23Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-07T08:47:23Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/11/07/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/120.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/120.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; a cup of tea in Moc Chau" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early in the morning, we left our accommodation and headed west from &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt;. Moc Chau is about 180 km away from the capital and it took us several hours to get there. On the way, we made a couple of stops which provided nice views of a landscape dotted with small cone-shaped mounds. But those stops also showed how a big problem all the ubiquitous rubbish was. A view of skinny cows which were looking for a last bunch of fresh grass among heaps of plastic bags was pretty&amp;nbsp;sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/112.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A snack break on the way to Moc Chau" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/112.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A snack break on the way to Moc Chau&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After midday, we arrived at our &lt;a href="https://www.agoda.com/moc-chau-arena-village/hotel/moc-chau-vn.html?cid=-218"&gt;accommodation&lt;/a&gt; in Moc Chau. The homestay itself was surrounded by a lovely tea plantation with good views of hills in the distance. We stayed in a simply equipped but spacious dorm with two other girls. As a welcome drink, we got a cup of tea which was so strong that it could easily replace a&amp;nbsp;shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/125.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A tea plantation in Moc Chau" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/125.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A tea plantation in Moc Chau&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, the only downside of that accommodation was food. The selection of meals was not a good fit for us. Personally, I’m not a fan of too fatty meat or frog’s legs. So, eventually, I settled for plain rice and cabbage. Better than a rumbling&amp;nbsp;belly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/116.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of village near by" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/116.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;View of village near by&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to our homestay was a short loop walk inside the tea plantation. Later, we also went to a tiny workshop where they did all the work which followed after a harvest – drying and packaging the tea. Although, at the time of our visit big drying pans were turned off. The lady at the workshop did a tea tasting for us with multiple samples of their own tea. As we quite liked some of those, we bought two small packages of the tea. Unfortunately, later at home when we tried them, we realized that they were of much lower quality than the ones at the&amp;nbsp;workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/118.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Local pets" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/118.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Local pets&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then our guide took us for a stroll to a nearby village. After experiencing busy Hanoi it was a nice change and we enjoyed a calm atmosphere there. We passed a house where wedding preparations were going on. When we left the village we carried on along the path which winded among fields. There were only a few houses on the surrounding hillsides and everything looked&amp;nbsp;peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/122.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Stroll around ethnic village in Moc Chau" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/122.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Stroll around ethnic village in Moc Chau&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we drove to Moc Chau town. As a first thing we climbed up to &lt;a href="http://www.vietnamculturetravel.com/vietnam-culture-guide/bat-cave-hang-doi/info.html"&gt;Doi Cave&lt;/a&gt;. The vast cave was embellished with awesome stalactites and from the main room there was a number of narrow footpaths which led to other tiny chambers. On the ceiling we could identify marks from bats which gave it its name – Bat&amp;nbsp;Cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/128.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Doi Cave" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/128.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Doi Cave&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was Ang Village. There was a lake surrounded by pine forest where we rented tandem bikes and went for a ride around the lake. Although riding that type of bike looked pretty easy, it took us a while to manage to coordinate our movements and keep the bike going straight. Even if the path was nicely flat and paved. Once we got on a bit harsh terrain I rather jumped off the bike than end up with bloody&amp;nbsp;knees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/132.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Somewhere on the way" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/132.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Somewhere on the way&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last bit for the day before we headed back to Hanoi was an orchid garden. It was located just a few minutes drive from the lake but could have been easily skipped because it was not worth it. Moreover, it was not a blooming season. So, we only saw a bunch of green plants, apart from few exceptions, and one poor bird of prey locked in a small cage. It seemed to be just a time killer to fill the schedule before we hit the road&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/135.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="In the orchid garden" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/135.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;In the orchid garden&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a part of the plan we were originally supposed to go to see the Dai Yem waterfall. However, our guide advised us that there had been some work done on a hydro power station and therefore there was hardly any water left in the&amp;nbsp;waterfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-10-01:/trips/2017/10/01/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; Perfume Pagoda and smoked porcupines</title>
    <published>2017-10-01T06:52:50Z</published>
    <updated>2017-10-01T06:52:50Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/10/01/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/79.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/79.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; Perfume Pagoda and smoked porcupines" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After early morning arrival from &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/09/17/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/"&gt;north Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;, we quickly dropped our bags at the hotel before our guide picked us up and we hit the road again. This time we drove about 60km from &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt; to the landscape of limestone hills where, in karst cliffs, lies one of Vietnam’s most famous pilgrim site – Perfume&amp;nbsp;Pagoda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/73.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="On the way to the Perfume Pagoda " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/73.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;On the way to the Perfume Pagoda &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at My Duc where we got on a row-boat. It took us to the foot of the mountain where the complex lied. But first of all, we had to wait for two other girls from our group who went to buy offerings and had to do some paperwork for their wishes. The place is extremely busy from February to April when Vietnamese people from a whole country come here to pray. Those two girls were from Ho Chi Minh&amp;nbsp;city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/75.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Boats parked at the foot of the mountain" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/75.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Boats parked at the foot of the mountain&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While rowing up the river, we enjoyed views of the flooded valley with its green hills and rice fields. Other passing boats with Vietnamese people were obviously enjoying a view of us and didn’t hesitate to take a picture either – we felt like&amp;nbsp;celebrities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/80.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Chua Thien Chu" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/80.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Chua Thien Chu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got off the boat, we headed to Chua Thien Chu – a temple from the 17th century. The place was very busy but pavilions and pagodas were beautiful and there was a nice smell of incense in the&amp;nbsp;air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/82.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Chua Thien Chu" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/82.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Chua Thien Chu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left the complex and went to a restaurant where we were going to meet our guide for lunch. The selection of food was broad. From classic chicken, pork or beef to snakes, smoked squirrels or porcupines. The meals we got were quite standard, although Jakub and my brother were convinced that the staff mixed a few pieces of snake meat into&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/77.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="What’s for lunch? A porcupine" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/77.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;What’s for lunch? A porcupine&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we grabbed a cable car to the summit. A one-way ticket was included in the price of the tour, so we chose to have a ride up and then walk down&amp;nbsp;later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/87.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Offerings at the entrance of Perfume Pagoda" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/87.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Offerings at the entrance of Perfume Pagoda&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cave itself was about 10 minutes walk from a top cable car station and we had to descent about 100 steps down to its entrance. The whole place was overcrowded with Vietnamese visitors. Each corner inside the cave was filled up with flowers, fruit, candles and other offerings which people brought. All that covered in clouds of&amp;nbsp;incense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/88.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Perfume Pagoda " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/88.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Perfume Pagoda &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back to the boat, we walked the path which was lined with stalls all the way down. People were selling all different kinds of stuff but mostly souvenirs which looked pretty tacky. We only bought some traditional cinnamon crackers which were&amp;nbsp;tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/85.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The whole place is hidden among limestone hills" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/85.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The whole place is hidden among limestone hills&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the trip was an interesting experience. We visited the place in its busiest time of the year and it was interesting to see so many people, some of them traveling from the other side of the country just to put an offering inside the pagoda and pray. We only noticed a couple of foreigners. So, a pure Vietnamese&amp;nbsp;experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>

