<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:base="https://barakuba.com/">
  <id>https://barakuba.com/</id>
  <title>Bára &amp; Kuba on the road :: The travel diary of two</title>
  <updated>2018-02-03T05:12:53Z</updated>
  <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/"/>
  <link rel="self" href="https://barakuba.com/feed/index.xml"/>
  <author>
    <name>Barbora Hájková &amp; Jakub Chodounský</name>
    <uri>https://barakuba.com</uri>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2018-02-03:/trips/2018/02/03/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; busy life of the Mekong delta</title>
    <published>2018-02-03T05:12:53Z</published>
    <updated>2018-02-03T05:12:53Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2018/02/03/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/164.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/164.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; busy life of the Mekong delta" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After two weeks in northern Vietnam, we flew from &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt; down south to Ho Chi Minh to spend the rest of our trip there. To keep the expenses low, we chose the Jetstar airlines for our flight. They are cheap but not particularly reliable and so, it didn’t surprise us when we took off with two hours delay. Classic&amp;nbsp;Jetstar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/158.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A floating market with all different kind of goods" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/158.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A floating market with all different kind of goods&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the airport in Ho Chi Minh, we wanted to avoid a hassle with bargaining the price of a taxi and used the Uber instead. We didn’t have to negotiate the price but talking to the driver on phone and finding the car was not easy&amp;nbsp;either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we knew that we would arrive late at night, we’d booked our &lt;a href="https://www.agoda.com/vinh-chung-hotel/hotel/ho-chi-minh-city-vn.html?cid=-177"&gt;hotel&lt;/a&gt; in advance. Rooms were very simple, nothing luxurious, but they were clean, had windows and most importantly – an&amp;nbsp;air-conditioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/166.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="One of smaller boats got closer to try to sell some of their fruit" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/166.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One of smaller boats got closer to try to sell some of their fruit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the next day we’d planned a trip to the Mekong Delta. A man picked us up early in the morning at our hotel and took us to a meeting point where we waited for a transport. For all our organized trips we always required to be a part of a very small group and so far it had always worked out. Until that time! A large packed bus with 30 other people&amp;nbsp;arrived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, after being squeezed on the bus for a few hours, we arrived at Cai Be where the hot air slapped us immediately when we got off. We boarded a motorized boat and headed to the floating market. Each of oncoming boats was loaded with different types of fruit or vegetable and sellers kept trying to slip the samples of their goods to us from tall wooden poles. After a while, we parked next to one of the boats and had a chance to buy some of the tasty&amp;nbsp;stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/159.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A refreshing coconut water" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/159.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A refreshing coconut water&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We carried on to a rice noodles and a paper factory. But, before that we had to have a useless 30 minutes break inside a souvenir&amp;nbsp;shop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The factory itself, which was rather a small backyard workshop than anything else, was quite interesting place. Both our guide and workers made an effort to explain and to show us a whole process of making the noodles and the rice paper. Volunteers could even try to make the paper on their own. Aside the other workers prepared coconut candies. We tasted a few  pieces along with some other pastries but all of them were too way too&amp;nbsp;sweet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/168.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A process of making rice noodles" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/168.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A process of making rice noodles&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, we hopped back on the boat and it took us to a different place where we had lunch. Again, all the food was delicious. The most interesting was a fish. At first, we hesitated to eat it because it looked a bit dodgy but then we plucked up the&amp;nbsp;courage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/163.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Our lunch included a local fish" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/163.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our lunch included a local fish&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we had a choice to go for a short push bike ride. The bikes were not in the best condition but good enough for a small loop in near surrounding before we headed back to the&amp;nbsp;boat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cruised for a few minutes before we got to our next stop. There, we were given traditional cone hats and got into small rowing boats operated by paddling women. They manoeuvred us through narrow river canals surrounded by dense vegetation before we got to a small wharf. From there we walked back to our boat on dry ground with a small stop for a cultural performance which was not very good&amp;nbsp;though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/162.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A part of the tour was also a demonstration from local beekeeper " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/162.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A part of the tour was also a demonstration from local beekeeper &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the last stop for the day. After returning back to the main wharf the bus supposed to take us to our accommodation. Or at least that’s what we thought was a plan. Instead, we stopped in the middle of nowhere and our guide told us we have to swap a bus because that  one was going to go back to Ho Chi Minh. We had to run across a busy four-lane highway, including climbing over concrete panels and waited in a odd place for a second bus. Luckily, it came soon and a couple of hours later we finally got to our hotel in Can&amp;nbsp;Tho.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/161.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Packaging of coconut candies " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/161.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Packaging of coconut candies &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After dinner, which was an interesting seafood hot pot, we went for a walk on a nice waterfront along the city’s river. It was full of busy bars and&amp;nbsp;restaurants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second part of the tour we started the next day early in the morning. The bus full of other people picked us up and we headed to the wharf where a boat had been already waiting for&amp;nbsp;us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/167.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rice paper drying on the sun" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/167.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Rice paper drying on the sun&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We cruised one of the river branches for about an hour before we made a break at a fruit orchard. It was a nice walk among fruit trees concluded with a fruit tasting and opportunity to buy some exotic pieces. No doubts that the prices were much higher than&amp;nbsp;usual.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got back to our boat we kept cruising for another hour but then it was time to slowly get back to our bus and head to Ho Chi&amp;nbsp;Minh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/155.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ho CHi Minh -- Post Office" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-busy-life-of-the-mekong-delta/155.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ho CHi Minh &amp;#8211; Post Office&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the trip was an interesting insight into life in delta but its value was degraded especially due to a very big group of people on the tour, too much waiting and useless stops at souvenir shops or because of that weird transport organization. Those things definitely need some&amp;nbsp;improvements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-11-27:/trips/2017/11/27/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; cruising in Bai Tu Long</title>
    <published>2017-11-27T08:17:39Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-27T08:17:39Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/11/27/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/142.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/142.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; cruising in Bai Tu Long" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;When we’d been organizing our trip to Ha Long Bay I was full of doubts. Many resources referred to the place as a location with thousands of tourist and hundreds of boats which cruise the bay all day long. After reading different resources and reviews we’d decided to do an overnight cruise in less known Bai Tu Long. It was a good&amp;nbsp;choice!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/146.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="What a day for a cruise" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/146.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;What a day for a cruise&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our trip was organized via &lt;a href="http://www.vietnamista.cz/news/cely-clanek/"&gt;Mrs Mai&lt;/a&gt;. Early in the morning, a guide picked us up at our accommodation in &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt; and we headed to Ha Long city. It took a few hours, so we arrived at Hon Gai wharf about midday. Within 15 minutes we were already boarding on a small boat which was going to take us to our wooden cruise boat. No&amp;nbsp;delays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/141.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A busy spot near Thien Canh Son cave" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/141.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A busy spot near Thien Canh Son cave&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beside us, there was only one Australian couple and a crew. It was almost like having a private trip. No crowds, no people stepping on each other’s&amp;nbsp;heads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cabins looked amazing. Wooden interior, a double bed, a nice bathroom and a big window for a proper view. We were chilling out only for a couple of minutes when somebody knocked on the door and announced the lunch&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/136.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside our cabin" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/136.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside our cabin&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch we went out on deck to admire the beautiful scenery. Rugged islands of different sizes and shapes were jutting all around and water sparkle in the afternoon sunshine. We could not have had the better&amp;nbsp;weather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/145.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Chilling on the deck" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/145.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Chilling on the deck&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We anchored near Thien Canh Son cave. A small boat took us to the shore and with our guide, we climbed stairs up to the cave entrance. It was the only time that day when we had to interact with a bunch of other tourists. The cave itself was nice but nothing amazing. But it had an interesting history. Before listed in &lt;span class="caps"&gt;UNESCO&lt;/span&gt;, the cave served as a party venue. Due to that fact, some formations inside the cave suffered from&amp;nbsp;vandalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/143.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Thien Canh Son cave " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/143.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Thien Canh Son cave &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we returned back to the boat it was time to do some exercise! We got on kayaks and paddled around one of the small islands. I was quite surprised how clean the water was. We only saw a couple of floating plastic bottles and packages. It was a big difference compared to rest of the countryside overloaded which garbage. It didn’t take long and we were jumping from the boat deck into the deep&amp;nbsp;water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/144.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A bit of exercise before Happy Hour" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/144.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A bit of exercise before Happy Hour&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the sunset, we joined some of our crew members for squid fishing. While they were attracting the squids with a torch, we were trying to catch them with a simple bamboo stick and a hook made of a wire. It seemed hopeless but eventually, Jakub caught one! Next day it was served for&amp;nbsp;lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/137.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A chef prepared a yummy lunch" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/137.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A chef prepared a yummy lunch&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night on the boat was great. While anchored in a sheltered area, the boat hardly swayed and the next day we realized that we were moving only because of a roaring&amp;nbsp;engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, we headed to Vung Vieng floating village. We got on a small rowing boat and paddled through small settlement. The houses were tiny, usually one bedroom with hammocks on front deck. Some households even had a dog but we felt a bit sorry for them as their movement was restricted to floating&amp;nbsp;boardwalks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/152.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Vung Vieng floating village" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/152.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Vung Vieng floating village&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole place was really quiet and peaceful which was in high contrast with busy La Ha Long. The journey to the village ended with dipping through the cave carved through one of the rocky&amp;nbsp;pillars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/153.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rowing through the arc near floating Vung Vieng village" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/153.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Rowing through the arc near floating Vung Vieng village&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we returned back to our boat, it was time to check out from our rooms. From floating village, we were heading back to the wharf. We had one more delicious lunch (including Jakub’s squid) and after that, we just hung around on the deck and enjoyed the&amp;nbsp;view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/147.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A beautiful sunset in Bai Tu Long" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-cruising-in-bai-tu-long/147.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A beautiful sunset in Bai Tu Long&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our driver picked us up at the harbor and we drove back to Hanoi. In the evening we were going to catch a plane to Ho Chi Minh where we would stay until the end of the&amp;nbsp;trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-11-07:/trips/2017/11/07/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; a cup of tea in Moc Chau</title>
    <published>2017-11-07T08:47:23Z</published>
    <updated>2017-11-07T08:47:23Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/11/07/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/120.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/120.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; a cup of tea in Moc Chau" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early in the morning, we left our accommodation and headed west from &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt;. Moc Chau is about 180 km away from the capital and it took us several hours to get there. On the way, we made a couple of stops which provided nice views of a landscape dotted with small cone-shaped mounds. But those stops also showed how a big problem all the ubiquitous rubbish was. A view of skinny cows which were looking for a last bunch of fresh grass among heaps of plastic bags was pretty&amp;nbsp;sad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/112.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A snack break on the way to Moc Chau" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/112.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A snack break on the way to Moc Chau&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After midday, we arrived at our &lt;a href="https://www.agoda.com/moc-chau-arena-village/hotel/moc-chau-vn.html?cid=-218"&gt;accommodation&lt;/a&gt; in Moc Chau. The homestay itself was surrounded by a lovely tea plantation with good views of hills in the distance. We stayed in a simply equipped but spacious dorm with two other girls. As a welcome drink, we got a cup of tea which was so strong that it could easily replace a&amp;nbsp;shot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/125.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A tea plantation in Moc Chau" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/125.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A tea plantation in Moc Chau&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, the only downside of that accommodation was food. The selection of meals was not a good fit for us. Personally, I’m not a fan of too fatty meat or frog’s legs. So, eventually, I settled for plain rice and cabbage. Better than a rumbling&amp;nbsp;belly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/116.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of village near by" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/116.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;View of village near by&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next to our homestay was a short loop walk inside the tea plantation. Later, we also went to a tiny workshop where they did all the work which followed after a harvest – drying and packaging the tea. Although, at the time of our visit big drying pans were turned off. The lady at the workshop did a tea tasting for us with multiple samples of their own tea. As we quite liked some of those, we bought two small packages of the tea. Unfortunately, later at home when we tried them, we realized that they were of much lower quality than the ones at the&amp;nbsp;workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/118.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Local pets" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/118.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Local pets&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then our guide took us for a stroll to a nearby village. After experiencing busy Hanoi it was a nice change and we enjoyed a calm atmosphere there. We passed a house where wedding preparations were going on. When we left the village we carried on along the path which winded among fields. There were only a few houses on the surrounding hillsides and everything looked&amp;nbsp;peaceful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/122.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Stroll around ethnic village in Moc Chau" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/122.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Stroll around ethnic village in Moc Chau&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we drove to Moc Chau town. As a first thing we climbed up to &lt;a href="http://www.vietnamculturetravel.com/vietnam-culture-guide/bat-cave-hang-doi/info.html"&gt;Doi Cave&lt;/a&gt;. The vast cave was embellished with awesome stalactites and from the main room there was a number of narrow footpaths which led to other tiny chambers. On the ceiling we could identify marks from bats which gave it its name – Bat&amp;nbsp;Cave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/128.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Doi Cave" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/128.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Doi Cave&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our next stop was Ang Village. There was a lake surrounded by pine forest where we rented tandem bikes and went for a ride around the lake. Although riding that type of bike looked pretty easy, it took us a while to manage to coordinate our movements and keep the bike going straight. Even if the path was nicely flat and paved. Once we got on a bit harsh terrain I rather jumped off the bike than end up with bloody&amp;nbsp;knees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/132.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Somewhere on the way" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/132.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Somewhere on the way&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last bit for the day before we headed back to Hanoi was an orchid garden. It was located just a few minutes drive from the lake but could have been easily skipped because it was not worth it. Moreover, it was not a blooming season. So, we only saw a bunch of green plants, apart from few exceptions, and one poor bird of prey locked in a small cage. It seemed to be just a time killer to fill the schedule before we hit the road&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/135.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="In the orchid garden" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-a-cup-of-tea-in-moc-chau/135.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;In the orchid garden&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a part of the plan we were originally supposed to go to see the Dai Yem waterfall. However, our guide advised us that there had been some work done on a hydro power station and therefore there was hardly any water left in the&amp;nbsp;waterfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-10-01:/trips/2017/10/01/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; Perfume Pagoda and smoked porcupines</title>
    <published>2017-10-01T06:52:50Z</published>
    <updated>2017-10-01T06:52:50Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/10/01/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/79.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/79.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; Perfume Pagoda and smoked porcupines" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;After early morning arrival from &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/09/17/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/"&gt;north Vietnam&lt;/a&gt;, we quickly dropped our bags at the hotel before our guide picked us up and we hit the road again. This time we drove about 60km from &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt; to the landscape of limestone hills where, in karst cliffs, lies one of Vietnam’s most famous pilgrim site – Perfume&amp;nbsp;Pagoda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/73.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="On the way to the Perfume Pagoda " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/73.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;On the way to the Perfume Pagoda &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We arrived at My Duc where we got on a row-boat. It took us to the foot of the mountain where the complex lied. But first of all, we had to wait for two other girls from our group who went to buy offerings and had to do some paperwork for their wishes. The place is extremely busy from February to April when Vietnamese people from a whole country come here to pray. Those two girls were from Ho Chi Minh&amp;nbsp;city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/75.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Boats parked at the foot of the mountain" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/75.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Boats parked at the foot of the mountain&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While rowing up the river, we enjoyed views of the flooded valley with its green hills and rice fields. Other passing boats with Vietnamese people were obviously enjoying a view of us and didn’t hesitate to take a picture either – we felt like&amp;nbsp;celebrities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/80.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Chua Thien Chu" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/80.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Chua Thien Chu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got off the boat, we headed to Chua Thien Chu – a temple from the 17th century. The place was very busy but pavilions and pagodas were beautiful and there was a nice smell of incense in the&amp;nbsp;air.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/82.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Chua Thien Chu" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/82.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Chua Thien Chu&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left the complex and went to a restaurant where we were going to meet our guide for lunch. The selection of food was broad. From classic chicken, pork or beef to snakes, smoked squirrels or porcupines. The meals we got were quite standard, although Jakub and my brother were convinced that the staff mixed a few pieces of snake meat into&amp;nbsp;it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/77.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="What’s for lunch? A porcupine" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/77.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;What’s for lunch? A porcupine&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we grabbed a cable car to the summit. A one-way ticket was included in the price of the tour, so we chose to have a ride up and then walk down&amp;nbsp;later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/87.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Offerings at the entrance of Perfume Pagoda" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/87.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Offerings at the entrance of Perfume Pagoda&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The cave itself was about 10 minutes walk from a top cable car station and we had to descent about 100 steps down to its entrance. The whole place was overcrowded with Vietnamese visitors. Each corner inside the cave was filled up with flowers, fruit, candles and other offerings which people brought. All that covered in clouds of&amp;nbsp;incense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/88.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Perfume Pagoda " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/88.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Perfume Pagoda &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back to the boat, we walked the path which was lined with stalls all the way down. People were selling all different kinds of stuff but mostly souvenirs which looked pretty tacky. We only bought some traditional cinnamon crackers which were&amp;nbsp;tasty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/85.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The whole place is hidden among limestone hills" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-perfume-pagoda-and-smoked-porcupines/85.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The whole place is hidden among limestone hills&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the trip was an interesting experience. We visited the place in its busiest time of the year and it was interesting to see so many people, some of them traveling from the other side of the country just to put an offering inside the pagoda and pray. We only noticed a couple of foreigners. So, a pure Vietnamese&amp;nbsp;experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-09-17:/trips/2017/09/17/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; chilly Sapa and monstrous Fansipan</title>
    <published>2017-09-17T05:30:24Z</published>
    <updated>2017-09-17T05:30:24Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/09/17/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/68.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/68.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; chilly Sapa and monstrous Fansipan" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A journey to Sapa took a couple of hours. The road was winding up to the hill and if the constant mist had not covered the whole area, the views would have been amazing. Unfortunately, it was wintertime and we fully noticed that when we stepped out of the bus. Sapa town lies at an elevation of about 1500m and the temperature was well below&amp;nbsp;10°C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/64.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Muong Hoa Valley" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/64.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Muong Hoa Valley&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That meant our only condition for an accommodation was a heater. The first hotel we walked in didn’t have one but the hotel next door, &lt;a href="http://www.saparubyhotel.com/"&gt;Sapa Ruby Hotel&lt;/a&gt;, had heat pumps in all rooms. For 30 &lt;span class="caps"&gt;NZD&lt;/span&gt; per night  we had a luxurious warm room. Although when we tried to make a tea a kettle cable caught on fire which was, on the other hand, promptly fixed by hotel staff – with a piece of duct&amp;nbsp;tape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/71.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="On the way to Love Waterfall" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/71.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;On the way to Love Waterfall&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following two days we tried a number of different restaurants and cafes in town. We liked a place called &lt;a href="https://www.tripadvisor.co.nz/Restaurant_Review-g311304-d8872739-Reviews-Sapa_24_Restaurant-Sapa_Lao_Cai_Province.html"&gt;24 Restaurant&lt;/a&gt; where we went twice. On Cau May, which is one of the busiest streets in town, we went to &lt;a href="https://www.tripadvisor.co.nz/Restaurant_Review-g311304-d4359144-Reviews-Little_SaPa_Restaurant-Sapa_Lao_Cai_Province.html"&gt;Little Sapa&lt;/a&gt; and few other places. We were not really impressed with &lt;a href="https://www.tripadvisor.co.nz/Restaurant_Review-g311304-d1119112-Reviews-Baguette_Chocolat_Cafe-Sapa_Lao_Cai_Province.html"&gt;Baguette &lt;span class="amp"&gt;&amp;amp;&lt;/span&gt; Chocolate&lt;/a&gt; but they had heaters on so we got warm at&amp;nbsp;least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/63.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Another misty view of Muong Hoa Valley" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/63.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Another misty view of Muong Hoa Valley&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We started our first day with a trip to &lt;a href="http://www.trekkingsapa.com/guide/muong-hoa-valley/"&gt;Muong Hoa Valley&lt;/a&gt;. It was about a half an hour drive from Sapa and it was a popular place for its beautiful views of rice fields and also the ethnic minorities people (H’mong and&amp;nbsp;Dao).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our driver dropped us off and we descended down to Muong Hoa River. Right when we got off the car, kids came to us trying to sell their pieces of work. It was hard to escape from&amp;nbsp;them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/66.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="In front of local school -- Muong Hoa Valley" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/66.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;In front of local school &amp;#8211; Muong Hoa Valley&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed a local school where a small group of kids was taking a lesson. We crossed the bridge over the river and went to a workshop where we learned about a traditional way of making clothes. Our guide also told us that different tribes can be recognized by a different type of clothes. Then we passed hamlets of Y Linh Ho and &lt;a href="http://www.trekkingsapa.com/guide/lao-chai-village-sapa/"&gt;Lao Chai&lt;/a&gt; where H’Mong people’s lived and our walk finished near Ta Van village which was settled by Dao&amp;nbsp;people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/65.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Kids taking a lesson at local school -- Muong Hoa Valley" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/65.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Kids taking a lesson at local school &amp;#8211; Muong Hoa Valley&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For lunch, we accepted our guide’s invitation and went to her grandma’s house. We walked up to the hill until we came to a shelter. Hens and kittens were running around. An old woman greeted us and invited us inside. The house was furnished with a few pieces of furniture and there was an open fire pit on one side. The walls with no windows were black from soot. The space under the roof was stacked with rice bags. For a moment we thought that we had not been food poisoned yet but that would be a real&amp;nbsp;test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/67.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="During our walk through hamlets in Muong Hoa Valley" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/67.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;During our walk through hamlets in Muong Hoa Valley&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in reality the food we got was absolutely delicious. There were different types of meat and vegetables. A lot of it. While we were having the feast, the grandma cut a piece of meat hanging above the fire pit and fried a bit of bacon too.&amp;nbsp;Yummy!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With full tummies we finished our walk at Ta Van village and waited for our driver to take us over to &lt;a href="http://www.trekkingsapa.com/guide/cat-cat-village-sapa/"&gt;Cat Cat Village&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cat Cat Village was only 3km from Sapa and was a home of Black H’Mong. As it was much easier accessible, it was also much more touristic and houses had been converted to souvenir shops. When we descended to the bottom of the valley, there was a nice waterfall and an interesting water structure from bamboo trunks consisting of watermills and floating decks. We also attended a short performance of traditional dances but it was a bit average. A classic tourist&amp;nbsp;trap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/69.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cat Cat Village" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/69.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cat Cat Village&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day the weather didn’t get any better and we said goodbye to any spectacular views. After breakfast, we drove along the winding road up to Tram Ton Pass which is the highest pass in Vietnam at an elevation of 1900m. However, even that altitude was not enough and all those amazing views we had read about were covered in&amp;nbsp;clouds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/72.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Love Waterfall" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/72.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Love Waterfall&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later on the way, we stopped at two waterfalls. The first one was called Love Waterfall. It’s a 100m high waterfall and to get there we walked through a nicely maintained area. A bit further along the road was the second one – Silver Waterfall. The stairs took us about 200m up to get a better view of cascading&amp;nbsp;water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/4.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="In the cabin -- from the bottom to the top" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/4.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;In the cabin &amp;#8211; from the bottom to the top&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way back to Sapa we decided to try our luck and go to Fansipan. Since 2016 there has been a cable car which takes people to the summit. As we didn’t have any hiking equipment, time and neither good weather it was a good alternative to a 2-day trip which could otherwise be organized with a guide. Also, we had heard gossips that it’s no longer worth the effort as they had been building a huge complex around the&amp;nbsp;summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/1.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Rush hour at the summit" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Rush hour at the summit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, it was only me and my mum who went up. Boys stayed down at the station. We shared a cabin with a group of really excited people from Ho Chi Minh, so after 20 minutes ride we were glad we got out. But more importantly, as we were getting closer to the top the clouds dispersed and the sun came&amp;nbsp;out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/2.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="View of surrounding mountains" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;View of surrounding mountains&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we got out of the cable car I could understand why people who decided to hike to the peak talked about&amp;nbsp;disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/3.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The enormous construction around the summit" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The enormous construction around the summit&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The whole area was a huge construction site. There was even another small cable car which could take tourists to the very top instead of climbing up the last 600 steps. No wonder that we met a few people on high heels. But still, we appreciated the view. The best in last two&amp;nbsp;days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/62.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The last view of rice terraces in Muong Hoa Valley" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-chilly-sapa-and-monstrous-fansipan/62.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The last view of rice terraces in Muong Hoa Valley&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that was it. We wrapped our staying in north Vietnam with one more delicious meal and one crazy drive on a bus back to Lao Cai. There, we took an overnight train back to warm&amp;nbsp;Hanoi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-09-05:/trips/2017/09/05/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; friendly homestay and incredible market in Bac Ho</title>
    <published>2017-09-05T15:25:09Z</published>
    <updated>2017-09-05T15:25:09Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/09/05/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/35.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/35.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; friendly homestay and incredible market in Bac Ho" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the evening, we arrived at &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt; Railway Station where we were about to get on an overnight train to Lao Cai. Initially, we struggled a bit with finding a stall where we had to pick up our tickets and then couldn’t find a right platform, but eventually, we achieved&amp;nbsp;both.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/34.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bac Ho Town - chilly and misty" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/34.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bac Ho Town - chilly and misty&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The train to Lao Cai looked like the Oriental Express. A compartment with two bunk beds was decorated with wood and lighted with little old fashioned lamps. Water and little snacks were also included. The only sign of modern technology were speakers crackling&amp;nbsp;terribly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/32.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hoang Yen Chao Castle in Bac Ho" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/32.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hoang Yen Chao Castle in Bac Ho&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night on moving train was a quite comfortable and in the morning, when we got off in Lao Cai, we were fairly fresh. Our guide, who was by the way in the 39th week of her pregnancy, picked us up and after a quick breakfast in an adjacent restaurant we set off to Bac&amp;nbsp;Ho.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/33.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Hoang Yen Chao Castle in Bac Ho" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/33.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Hoang Yen Chao Castle in Bac Ho&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bac Ho was a small town and we chose to stay in a homestay which was run by a local family. We were keen to try this style of accommodation to get some authentic experience and have a closer insight into the lifestyle. Our homestay had a higher standard than a typical local house but it was still interesting to sit with the family around a fire pit, drink tea and crunch pumpkin&amp;nbsp;seeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/41.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A few minutes of better view - Bac Ho surroundings" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/41.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A few minutes of better view - Bac Ho surroundings&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the afternoon, we went for a walk around town. We strolled to a large mansion which served as a residence for a local governor in old the days. Nowadays, there is a souvenir shop and rice wine cooking stalls at the back of the&amp;nbsp;property.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/42.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Those peach blossoms were the only sign of good weather" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/42.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Those peach blossoms were the only sign of good weather&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From there, we moved further to the lake, passed a local school full of kids and walked the little streets where pigs and chickens ran in front of the houses. It was a chilly winter day and a whole town was wrapped into the smell of burned&amp;nbsp;firewood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, a friend of our host family took us for a trip to a near village where a Hmong minority lived. At first, we had to climb up through rice terraces. Unfortunately, at that time of the year, there were nothing but hollow muddy fields instead of beautiful colourful beds. In past few days it had also rained a lot, so all the paths were slippery and our 7kg carry on luggage didn’t allow for much of spare&amp;nbsp;clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/37.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view was terrible but terraces were really there all around" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/37.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A view was terrible but terraces were really there all around&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point our guide met a friend of his. Together we started to climb through the mud somewhere in the middle of nowhere and when we protested because of the lack of gumboots they totally ignored us. I started to be nervous that we would never get back&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Luckily, after a few hundred meters, we finally got to a little settlement with few houses where kids and domestic animals played together in a muddy open area. Locals looked quite excited when they saw foreign faces. In spare time, when our guide went for a quick welcome drink with his friend, we shyly looked around before we headed back to the&amp;nbsp;homestay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/38.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A remote settlement of Hmong minority" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/38.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A remote settlement of Hmong minority&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, we were all invited to dinner to the house of our host family friend. When we arrived, there was a gathering of 10 family members and friends. They had cooked all different kinds of dishes and washed it down with a proper amount of house rice wine. Seeing our driver drinking shots one after another we had doubts about our way home but in spite of that, a couple of hours later we got safely to our&amp;nbsp;beds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/45.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Our breakfast Pho is being prepared" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/45.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our breakfast Pho is being prepared&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early next day we set off to a village market. However, it was not an ordinary local market with a few types of veggies and fruits. Every Sunday people from surrounding villages come to sell and buy (or exchange) everything from food, cookware, clothes but also&amp;nbsp;animals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/58.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Eggs of all kinds, shapes, and colours" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/58.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Eggs of all kinds, shapes, and colours&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we walked through the market, we passed tables displaying all kinds of meat, bowls full of eggs or boxes with spices smelling nice. However, the most interesting was an area where animals were&amp;nbsp;traded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/43.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="You could buy a small horse" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/43.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;You could buy a small horse&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way to the market, we had met a woman carrying a pig in a bag on her back. We had thought it was dead but when we got to the animal trade area we realized that it is just the way people got their goods there. In boxes we saw little puppies and kittens, in cages, there were hens and roosters. Donkeys and little horses were kept&amp;nbsp;separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/46.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Or you could buy a big one" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/46.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Or you could buy a big one&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We climbed the steps to the top of a small mound. There was a square dedicated to the trade of buffaloes. Our guide told us that a buffalo could be sold for about 40 million dongs which was the equivalent of our second-hand car in New Zealand. Although, our Caldina provides a much more comfortable&amp;nbsp;ride.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/51.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Buffaloes have their own space on the top of little mound" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/51.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Buffaloes have their own space on the top of little mound&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We left the place just in time because two big buffaloes got a bit nervous and started to fight against each other which made it difficult for tiny owners to calm them&amp;nbsp;down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At last, we wrapped our staying with a ride on horse wagon around the town hills. It provided great views of rice terraces and the town itself, however, we couldn’t help but feel really sorry for a poor horse because at some parts of the track it struggled a&amp;nbsp;lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/49.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The essential equipment for housekeeping" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-friendly-homestay-and-incredible-market-in-bac-ho/49.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The essential equipment for housekeeping&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The end! Later in the afternoon, we drove over to foggy and cold Sapa which was our next stop for the next two&amp;nbsp;days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-07-06:/trips/2017/07/06/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; Tam Coc and Cuc Phuong</title>
    <published>2017-07-06T07:06:44Z</published>
    <updated>2017-07-06T07:06:44Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/07/06/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/12.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/12.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; Tam Coc and Cuc Phuong" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Originally, I had ambitions that we would organize the two-day trip to Tam Coc and Cuc Phuong on our own with the help of public transport. Yet, our laziness prevailed and we bought a tour which was offered at our&amp;nbsp;accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/10.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A bridge to the ancient capital" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/10.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A bridge to the ancient capital&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early in the morning, a guide picked us up at the hotel and with five other passengers, we hit the road to Ninh Binh city. It was a few hours long drive and after a couple of hours, we made a break at cafe/souvenir shop. It was one of those places where every tour group stops and prices are million times higher than everywhere else. A classic tourist&amp;nbsp;trap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/15.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A whole area is an archaeological site" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/15.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A whole area is an archaeological site&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About midday we arrived in Ninh Binh area and our first stop was at Hoa Lu. Hoa Lu was the ancient capital city of Vietnamese kingdom called Dai Co Viet in the 10th century. A nice bridge led over the river to the entrance gate where a man offered taking a picture with his buffalo. For a small donation of&amp;nbsp;course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/17.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A buffalo business" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/17.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A buffalo business&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the area, there was a number of temples, pagodas and courts. Inside temples, the statues of kings were surrounded by piles of offerings and everything was wrapped in veils of incense. The complex was surrounded by limestone hills which back in the past had provided protection against Chinese&amp;nbsp;invaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our guide, we also learn a bit about history and old&amp;nbsp;dynasties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/18.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Shipping spot for ride at Tam Coc" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/18.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Shipping spot for ride at Tam Coc&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, we moved on to Tam Coc. We had lunch at &lt;a href="http://thelongrestaurant.com/"&gt;restaurant&lt;/a&gt; nearby the lake but it was average, nothing&amp;nbsp;special.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After lunch, we got on small boats and rowers took us for two hours ride. Tam Coc is said to be a miniature landlocked version of Ha Long Bay. Our boat slowly peddled through the landscape of karst hills with rice paddies on sides. We went through three low-level tunnel caves which were eroded through the limestone hills and during rainy seasons are barely&amp;nbsp;passable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/26.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bright green colour of rice fields" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/26.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bright green colour of rice fields&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The place is a popular touristic spot, so even along canals, there are boats loaded with snacks and drinks and ready to attack passing boats. And of course, the rowers expected a tip at the end of the ride (on the top of the tickets we’d bought). My mom and brother totally overpaid their rower, so he said goodbye to them with a shiny smile on his face. On the other hand, our rower would have rather seen us down in the&amp;nbsp;water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/23.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="One of the three caves we passed through" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/23.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One of the three caves we passed through&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the night we stayed in a hotel somewhere in Ninh Binh. In the evening we went to explore the city but except a nice park with a Buddhist temple and a lookout with grey smog view, there was not much and the city didn’t impress&amp;nbsp;us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next day morning, after a few nervous moments, wondering whether our guide forgot about us and we would have to find our own way back to Hanoi, we set off to Cuc Phuong. Only with an hour&amp;nbsp;delay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/31.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Somewhere at Cuc Phuong National Park" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/31.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Somewhere at Cuc Phuong National Park&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cuc Phuong is the Vietnam’s first national park. Walks within the park allowed to explore the rainforest and the life in it. After we arrived to the park, firstly, we visited a primal rescue center where we saw all the different monkey species. While adults were lazily sitting on tree branches, babies were jumping and playing&amp;nbsp;around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few meters from there, there was a smaller turtle center. It was rather the informational center referring to attempts which had been made to increasing the number of those endangered animals but they had a few living pieces crawling around too.  Apparently, turtles are a pricey item on the black&amp;nbsp;market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/29.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="An ancient tree" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/29.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;An ancient tree&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the park, we made two short walks to ancient trees. Walks were a bit overgrown and muddy – which kind of made sense – it was a rainforest. Still, two young guys who were part of our group set off in flip flops. It wasn’t the best choice for steep slippery&amp;nbsp;parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We had lunch in a remote restaurant which looked more like a shelter in the middle of nowhere but meals were absolutely&amp;nbsp;delicious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/11.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Cold but exciting!" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-tam-coc-and-cuc-phuong/11.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Cold but exciting!&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the afternoon we spent on the way back to &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"&gt;Hanoi&lt;/a&gt;. In the evening we were going to get on a train and head off up north to Sapa region for few days. But about that – next&amp;nbsp;time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-06-27:/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/</id>
    <title type="html">Vietnam&amp;#58; Bun Cha in Hanoi</title>
    <published>2017-06-27T06:01:40Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-27T06:01:40Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/27/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/92.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/92.jpg" alt="Vietnam&amp;#58; Bun Cha in Hanoi" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We’d been planning this trip for a while. A lot of inspiration and useful information we found on Czech website &lt;a href="http://www.vietnamista.cz/"&gt;Vietnamista&lt;/a&gt;. It also helped us to sort out our visa, so after arrival, we didn’t have problems at immigration and everything went&amp;nbsp;smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After meeting with two other members of our group at the airport, withdrawing local money from &lt;span class="caps"&gt;ATM&lt;/span&gt; and a bit of struggling during buying a local sim card (Viettel) we finally headed off to our accommodation in central&amp;nbsp;Hanoi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/103.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The smell of burning incense accompanied us everywhere" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/103.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The smell of burning incense accompanied us everywhere&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first night, we’d booked rooms in &lt;a href="https://www.booking.com/hotel/vn/luminous-viet.cs.html?aid=304142;label=gen173nr-1FCA4oggJCAlhYSAViBW5vcmVmaK4BiAEBmAEFwgEKd2luZG93cyAxMMgBDNgBAegBAfgBBpICAXmoAgM;sid=095d466a6b99e95958ef967f846213c1;dest_id=-3714993;dest_type=city;dist=0;group_adults=2;group_children=0;hip_dst=1;hpos=1;no_rooms=1;room1=A%2CA;sb_price_type=total;srfid=ed025e83e2d05bb99dff3974404f1e60b362805fX1;type=total;ucfs=1&amp;amp;#hotelTmpl"&gt;Luminous Viet Hotel&lt;/a&gt;. The hotel was located in the Old Town center and rooms were nice, so eventually we stayed there for two other nights during our trip. Unfortunately, the third night we were not cautious enough, didn’t check the rooms and ended up with one room without windows. Lesson learned – always check the rooms beforehand, even if staying at the same place&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/1.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The entrance to Ngoc Son Temple" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The entrance to Ngoc Son Temple&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the day we spent wandering through the Old Town of Hanoi. The first impression was terrifying. An uncoordinated jungle of honking motorbikes and cars scared us and every single street crossing was like struggle for life. Even at a properly marked crossing with a traffic light, the situation wasn’t much better. However, after a while, we adjusted and followed the locals. One important rule – do not run across the road. It’s safer to keep going, slowly, and everybody gets around&amp;nbsp;you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/3.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Flowers, fruit and fake money are the most common offerings" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Flowers, fruit and fake money are the most common offerings&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We walked to Lake Hoan Kiem and visited &lt;a href="https://www.lonelyplanet.com/vietnam/hanoi/attractions/ngoc-son-temple/a/poi-sig/398071/357880"&gt;Ngoc Son Temple&lt;/a&gt;. It was located on a little island and as a Buddhist temple, it was full of flowers, fruit and other offerings which people brought there. It’s a famous touristic place which corresponded with crowds of people fighting for the best&amp;nbsp;picture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, we strolled to St Joseph Cathedral and then further to the &lt;a href="http://www.hanoitoursvietnam.com/Hanoi-Tourist-Sites/hoa-lo-prison-museum-the-hanoi-hilton.html"&gt;Hoa Lo Prison Museum&lt;/a&gt; which was an interesting insight into the Vietnam&amp;nbsp;history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/9.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Inside Hoa Lo Prison Museum" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/9.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Inside Hoa Lo Prison Museum&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we came back to Hanoi later that week for one more day, our next stop was Temple of Literature - Văn Mieu - Quốc Tu Giam. This temple, which is also the oldest Vietnamese university, is dedicated to Confucius. It’s a beautiful large complex with a lake, courts and parks and peaceful compared to what’s happening outside its&amp;nbsp;walls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/91.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The entrance to Văn Mieu - Quốc Tu Giam" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/91.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The entrance to Văn Mieu - Quốc Tu Giam&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not far away from there was One Pillar Pagoda – Chua Mot Cot. It’s a small but one of the most famous temples in Vietnam. Standing in the middle of a little pond, the temple should remind a lotus&amp;nbsp;blossom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/97.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Pagoda represents a lotus flower growing up out of the water" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/97.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Pagoda represents a lotus flower growing up out of the water&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a few steps away is Ho Chi Minh Museum and Mausoleum. We skipped visits of both of those places but interesting was that because of lunch break, all pathways around mausoleum were closed and guarded. Whoever came near the signs was promptly chased&amp;nbsp;off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/99.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Ho Chi Minh Mausoleum -- no entrance during lunch break" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/99.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Ho Chi Minh Mausoleum &amp;#8211; no entrance during lunch break&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before we headed back to the Old Town we visited Tran Quoc Pagoda. It was located on a small peninsula surrounded by West Lake. We arrived just in the middle of a ceremony which was sung via speakers and echoed all around the&amp;nbsp;place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/104.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Gathering at Tran Quoc Pagoda during the prayer" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/104.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Gathering at Tran Quoc Pagoda during the prayer&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wrapped up our stay in Hanoi with an evening performance in &lt;a href="http://thanglongwaterpuppet.org/en/"&gt;Water Puppet Theatre&lt;/a&gt;. The performance which lasted about 45 minutes consisted of several short stories and was accompanied by traditional Vietnamese music. Later our guide told us that it’s an attraction only for kids and tourists but we liked it&amp;nbsp;anyway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/109.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Water Puppet Show" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/vietnam-bun-cha-in-hanoi/109.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Water Puppet Show&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A whole different chapter could be dedicated to Vietnamese cuisine. For our first lunch, we tried a Hanoi specialty – &lt;a href="https://www.roughguides.com/article/10-vietnamese-foods-you-need-to-try/"&gt;bun cha&lt;/a&gt;. We heard stories that tourists get easy food poisoned in Asia, so initially, we wanted to take it easy and eat somewhere decent the first day. But our plans had changed as we were passing all kind of street restaurants and they all smelled great. A restaurant is actually not a right word. It was usually an eatery, right on the street with a few tiny plastic tables, stools, and a boiling pot right next to it. Eventually, we ended up at one of those trying not to think about hygiene.  We were the only foreigners there but it was a good sign in the end because the food was delicious! And we survived without any digestion&amp;nbsp;issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-06-18:/trips/2017/06/18/kepler-track/</id>
    <title type="html">Kepler Track</title>
    <published>2017-06-18T09:54:35Z</published>
    <updated>2017-06-18T09:54:35Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/06/18/kepler-track/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/7.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/7.jpg" alt="Kepler Track" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Most of the Great Walks need to be planned well ahead and the same stands for the &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/keplertrack"&gt;Kepler Track&lt;/a&gt; which is one of them. It is the 3-4 day walk, so we booked our hut tickets already in October for a long weekend in January. Unfortunately, campsites, which count for a cheaper accommodation option on Great Walks, are not well spread along the Kepler Track. Given the fortune we spent for hut tickets and flights, we really hoped for good weather, despite the bad weather&amp;nbsp;forecast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/6.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The Luxmore Hut - our first night destination" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/6.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The Luxmore Hut - our first night destination&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Friday we walked through the airport gate without any troubles even though our carry on backpacks weighed a bit over 7kg. Luckily, nobody checked&amp;nbsp;that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Dunedin, we picked up our El Cheapo from &lt;a href="https://www.jucy.co.nz"&gt;Jucy&lt;/a&gt; and carried on to Balclutha where we were going to stay the night. We knew about a nice &lt;a href="http://balcluthamotorcamp.co.nz"&gt;camp&lt;/a&gt; there as we’d already stayed there during our Christmas&amp;nbsp;travel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/36.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Almost as a mirror" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/36.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Almost as a mirror&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, when we approached Te Anau, the surrounding hills were covered by clouds. Once it started to drizzle, our last hopes for good weather had just&amp;nbsp;vanished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/31.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Lake Manapouri beach" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/31.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Lake Manapouri beach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Te Anau, we walked to &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/parks-and-recreation/places-to-go/fiordland/places/fiordland-national-park/fiordland-national-park-visitor-centre/"&gt;&lt;span class="caps"&gt;DOC&lt;/span&gt; center&lt;/a&gt; to pick up hut tickets and get their latest weather advice. It wasn’t good at all. A lot of rain and strong wind but apparently not bad enough to close the&amp;nbsp;track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/1.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The first part to Brod Bay campsite was flat and easy" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/1.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The first part to Brod Bay campsite was flat and easy&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we headed off. The first part of the track ran through beech forest along the shore of Lake Te Anau. At Brod Bay campsite the track turned away from the lake and we started to climb up. I was annoyed. All that effort ahead and money we spent for nothing. No more than rubbish views and wet clothes. After a while, my mumbling and complaining annoyed even Jakub. Moreover, blisters appeared on my heels. On the first day.&amp;nbsp;Perfect!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/2.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Jakub posing with limestone" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/2.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jakub posing with limestone&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We passed a massive limestone bluff before we got above bushline. It was a moment when we should have enjoyed panoramic views. What we really experienced was total mist and views of few meters&amp;nbsp;around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/3.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view above bushline -- not much" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/3.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A view above bushline &amp;#8211; not much&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After about 45 minutes we reached the Luxmore Hut. While having a snack we got a bit warm and as there still was plenty of daylight we went to explore Luxmore Caves which were nearby. A few stairs led down to the cave entrance and with a torch we could go quite deep into the cave. Definitely worth those 10 minutes walk from the&amp;nbsp;hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/5.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A view got better later in the evening" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/5.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A view got better later in the evening&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the evening the clouds raised up and we had a better view of the lake Te Anau and surrounding hills. However, a hut ranger didn’t put our hopes for better weather too high during his evening hut&amp;nbsp;talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/14.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The second day on the ridge was tough with gusts over 100km/hr" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/14.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The second day on the ridge was tough with gusts over 100km/hr&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the morning, he confirmed his predictions with the comment “It’s pretty brutal up there.” and added that groups with young kids should consider returning back to Te&amp;nbsp;Anau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After thinking it through over the breakfast and reassuring with the ranger twice that it would be tough but not dangerous, we set out&amp;nbsp;ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/12.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A desperate smile" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/12.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A desperate smile&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we left the hut, a cold wind hit our faces. It was strong but luckily most of the time we were sheltered behind the ridge. We rejected a side climb to Mt Luxmore summit and headed to the Forest Burn Shelter instead. On the way, we passed a number of other people and surprisingly even a group with small&amp;nbsp;kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The section between Forest Burn Shelter and Hanging Valley Shelter was rough. There were patches of snow on the path, it started to rain (horizontally thanks to the wind) and the temperature dropped down below zero due to wind chill factor. My trousers were covered with an icy&amp;nbsp;crust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/15.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Little waterfalls were everywhere in the forest " src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/15.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Little waterfalls were everywhere in the forest &lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst part was when we were passing one of the exposed saddles. The strong wind that rushed up through​ the valley along with gusts with speed over 100km/h made it really hard to stand on the narrow pathway. In the middle of the crossing, I suddenly saw Jakub’s backpack cover being blown away. At that point, I was quite scared and was thinking about going&amp;nbsp;back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, when we got over that section the conditions calmed down a bit and we reached the Hanging Valley Shelter in about 10 minutes. There, we met a couple who came from the other side of the track and they assured us the wind wasn’t so bad over&amp;nbsp;there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/11.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The best view of the second day with Lake Manapouri on the horizon" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/11.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The best view of the second day with Lake Manapouri on the horizon&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, the following part when we descended along the ridge to the Iris Burn Hut provided some good views of the valley and Lake Manapouri. Finally, the more pleasant half of the track&amp;nbsp;began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/19.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Iris Burn waterfall" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/19.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Iris Burn waterfall&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Iris Burn Hut was situated in a large tussock clearing and there were no signs of terrible weather which troubled us on the ridge. Inside the hut, a wood burner made it nice and warm. Refreshed and with dry clothes, we went to Iris Burn falls which was a 20 minutes side trip from the&amp;nbsp;hut.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A guide leaflet referred to the waterfall as a place suitable for a dip but after plenty of rain in the last few days, the waterfall was a quite massive and too whirling even for famous blue&amp;nbsp;ducks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/21.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A little friend" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/21.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A little friend&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening we listened to an interesting hut talk during which a ranger tried to imitate sounds of kiwi. His performance was a bit weird but it was authentic enough that later in the night when I woke up and heard a similar noise I knew it was a kiwi out there.&amp;nbsp;Yeah!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/25.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Jakub having a dip in the Lake Manapouri" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/25.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jakub having a dip in the Lake Manapouri&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day the track took us over an easily graded saddle, we passed a location where heavy rains caused a large slip in January 1984 before walked through lowland beech forest. We were almost eaten by sand flies during our lunch on side of Iris Burn. Early in the afternoon, we reached the shore of Lake Manapouri. While Jakub was having a refreshing dip, I enjoyed the sunshine. The Moturau Hut was located only a few hundred meters further and in the evening we observed a beautiful sunset over the lake on the&amp;nbsp;beach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/28.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Sunset at the Lake Manapouri" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/28.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Sunset at the Lake Manapouri&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last day was a bit struggle as our legs were wobbly after previous 3 days and 45km. The section walked across flat wetland and then followed the Waiau River. From swing bridge at Rainbow Reach, which was an optional end of the track, we still had 10km to finish the track. Despite aching feet, we refused to take a shuttle, clenched our teeth and carried&amp;nbsp;on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/35.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="A wetland area on the way to Rainbow Reach" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/35.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;A wetland area on the way to Rainbow Reach&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a real relief when we finally passed control gates at Te Anau Lake and got to our car after four&amp;nbsp;days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/kepler-track/40.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The last 10km to finish" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/kepler-track/40.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The last 10km to finish&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, the trip was not a waste of money. Those four days had everything – a lot of rain and a bit of sun, some wind and frost, little drama and enough fun. And most importantly, when we looked back we’d survived and enjoyed it&amp;nbsp;all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:barakuba.com,2017-04-17:/trips/2017/04/17/routeburn-track/</id>
    <title type="html">Routeburn Track</title>
    <published>2017-04-17T09:17:59Z</published>
    <updated>2017-04-17T09:17:59Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2017/04/17/routeburn-track/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/129.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img src="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/129.jpg" alt="Routeburn Track" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;In October 2016, we were planning our Christmas travel and we decided to take the advantage of being down in South Island and do another Great Walk. After &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/trips/2016/11/15/tongariro-northern-circuit/"&gt;Tongariro Northern Circuit&lt;/a&gt; it was going to be our second one. As the Kepler Track hut tickets were already sold out for suitable dates and the Milford Track was hopelessly booked out for the rest of the season, we chose the &lt;a href="http://www.doc.govt.nz/routeburntrack"&gt;Routeburn track&lt;/a&gt;..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/96.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Full of energy at the beginning of the track" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/96.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Full of energy at the beginning of the track&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Routeburn track is a one-way walk, so after deciding which way we would go, we needed to sort out our transportation. We started the track from The Divide and finished it at Routeburn Shelter. We considered different options, compared prices and eventually chose car relocation with &lt;a href="http://www.easyhike.co.nz/routeburn-track/routeburn-track-car-relocation/"&gt;Easy Hike&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/106.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="One of rare clear views on the track -- Hollyford Valley" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/106.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One of rare clear views on the track &amp;#8211; Hollyford Valley&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night before the track we stayed in &lt;a href="http://teanauholidaypark.co.nz/"&gt;Te Anau&lt;/a&gt;. In the morning, we went to do some final shopping and picked up a locker for a car key. We’d never done this type of car relocation before and after we got a little magnetic box which we supposed to snap to the bottom of the car, we could do nothing but hope that we would see our car ever&amp;nbsp;again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/140.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Route Burn Valley before descent to Routeburn Falls Hut -- our lunch break spot" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/140.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Route Burn Valley before descent to Routeburn Falls Hut &amp;#8211; our lunch break spot&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The weather in Te Anau wasn’t bad but as we were getting closer to The Divide, the surrounding hills got covered by clouds and it started to drizzle a&amp;nbsp;bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We set off the track shortly after noon. Over the night, we were going to stay at Lake Mackenzie campsite which was about 4 hours of walk away. No need to rush&amp;nbsp;then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/97.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The first stop on the track -- Lake Howden" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/97.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The first stop on the track &amp;#8211; Lake Howden&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The track ascended gradually and in 45 min we came to the junction to Key Summit. That is said to be a popular side track with a beautiful view but as the visibility was poor that day, we skipped it and carried on to Lake&amp;nbsp;Howden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/103.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="One of the numerous streams on the way" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/103.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;One of the numerous streams on the way&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the bench, in front of the hut at Lake Howden, we had a small snack. But shortly we rather carried on moving because a big guided group of people was just about finishing their fancy muffins and got ready to go too and we wanted to avoid any walking in&amp;nbsp;queues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/100.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The mystic Earland falls" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/100.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The mystic Earland falls&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along the next section of the track, the clouds cleared up a bit now and then and we had a better view of hills on the other side of Hollyford valley. Unfortunately, just when we reached the Earland Falls one of the clouds covered the mountain and we could hardly see the top of the&amp;nbsp;waterfall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, when we reached an open grassy area called “Orchard” even sun came out and we could fully enjoy the sunshine. The Orchard looked like an amazing place for camping but “No Camping” signs are located at both ends of this lovely&amp;nbsp;section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/105.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The weather got slightly better when we reached The Orchard" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/105.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The weather got slightly better when we reached The Orchard&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Lake Mackenzie, we arrived at the hut first. The campsite was located about 10 minutes further but notes around the hut clearly informed that campers are not allowed to use hut facilities. We were a bit surprised by such a differentiation between campers and hut guests. Especially because during our time at Tongariro Northern Circuit we stayed at the campsite but we were allowed to use the huts for cooking or&amp;nbsp;chilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/112.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Our overnight spot - Lake Mackenzie campsite" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/112.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Our overnight spot - Lake Mackenzie campsite&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the campsite, there was only one other tent but by the dusk, the area was fully&amp;nbsp;packed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before dinner, we explored the area around the lake. There is a short side trip to Split Rock. From the rock, the orange triangle signs led to the edge of the lake. The path was a bit overgrown and sometimes we had to struggle through branches but it was worth it because the lake shore was&amp;nbsp;charming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/117.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Last few moments with good weather while climbing up from Lake Mackenzie" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/117.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Last few moments with good weather while climbing up from Lake Mackenzie&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day morning we set off early as we were going to finish the rest of the track and still had planned to drive a bit further north before we would find a campsite for the&amp;nbsp;night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The section from Lake Mackenzie up to the hill was the only arduous ascend on the track. But once we climbed to a certain level, we easily traversed the exposed Hollyford Face. In good weather, according to our guide book, this part provides wonderful views over the Darran Mountains. Unfortunately, we walked in a total fog and didn’t see further than a few&amp;nbsp;meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/118.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Bara and … the fog" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/118.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Bara and … the fog&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then we passed Harris Saddle and on the other side of the ridge, the situation got finally better because all the clouds were caught by hills. There was a small shelter at Harris Saddle which was an ideal place for a&amp;nbsp;snack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/130.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Dark blue waters of Lake Harris" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/130.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Dark blue waters of Lake Harris&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following section of the track was really stunning. The track ran above black waters of Lake Harris and we enjoyed views of jagged mountains all around. Further behind the lake, we could see a high waterfall falling out from Lake&amp;nbsp;Wilson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/135.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="The winding Route Burn stream and its amazing valley" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/135.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;The winding Route Burn stream and its amazing valley&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the way down to Routeburn Falls Hut, we descended along a cascading stream which escalated into an impressive gorge and a beautiful combination of waterfalls right next to the hut. The hut was almost empty as all the people left already and we had a quiet lunch in a communal&amp;nbsp;kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/136.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Jakub safely covered under rock shelter" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/136.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Jakub safely covered under rock shelter&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Routeburn Falls Hut we descended steadily through beech forest and passed a few small waterfalls before we made a turn to Routeburn Flats Hut – our last stop on the track. The hut was on the edge of open grassy area with access to the river and views of the Humboldt&amp;nbsp;Mountains&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/145.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Routeburn Flats and view of Humboldt Mountains in the background" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/145.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Routeburn Flats and view of Humboldt Mountains in the background&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the track ran through the forest along the open area before it went over a swing bridge and then it winded above the gorge. Frankly, that section was a bit tedious and too long, so we were quite happy when we finally reached the carpark after a couple of&amp;nbsp;hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;a href="https://barakuba.com/photos/960x/routeburn-track/147.jpg" class="gallery-link"&gt;&lt;img alt="Route Burn stream crossing" src="https://barakuba.com/photos/640x/routeburn-track/147.jpg" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;Route Burn stream crossing&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we were even happier when we saw our relocated&amp;nbsp;car!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>

